Michael	B-Person
Pentella	E-Person
PhD	O
,	O
is	O
Director	O
of	O
the	O
Bureau	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Laboratory	I-Organization
Sciences	E-Organization
at	O
the	O
Hinton	B-Organization
State	I-Organization
Laboratory	I-Organization
Institute	E-Organization
,	O
Commonwealth	O
of	O
Massachusetts	S-Location
.	O
He	O
previously	O
served	O
as	O
the	O
Associate	O
Director	O
of	O
the	O
Iowa	B-Organization
state	I-Organization
public	I-Organization
health	I-Organization
laboratory	E-Organization
and	O
as	O
Clinical	O
Associate	O
Professor	O
at	O
the	O
College	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Public	I-Organization
Health	E-Organization
,	O
University	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Iowa	E-Organization
.Dr.	O
has	O
more	O
than	O
30	O
years	O
of	O
experience	O
in	O
clinical	O
and	O
public	O
health	O
laboratories	O
and	O
is	O
board	O
certified	O
in	O
medical	O
microbiology	O
and	O
infection	O
control	O
.	O

This	O
last	O
weekend	O
,	O
at	O
the	O
AAAS	B-Activity
Annual	I-Activity
Meeting	E-Activity
in	O
Austin	S-Location
,	O
Texas	S-Location
,	O
Col	O
.	O

Calkins	S-Person
said	O
the	O
lack	O
of	O
larvae	O
could	O
show	O
that	O
the	O
infestation	O
was	O
small	O
and	O
isolated	O
,	O
and	O
located	O
away	O
from	O
traps	O
.	O

The	O
Chinese	B-Organization
government	E-Organization
has	O
been	O
criticised	O
by	O
the	O
United	B-Organization
States	I-Organization
government	E-Organization
,	O
UK	S-Organization
Minister	O
for	O
the	O
Cabinet	O
Office	O
Michael	B-Person
Gove	E-Person
,	O
and	O
others	O
for	O
its	O
handling	O
of	O
the	O
pandemic	O
.	O

On	O
29	O
August	O
,	O
a	O
9-year-old	O
Congolese	O
girl	O
became	O
the	O
fourth	O
individual	O
in	O
Uganda	S-Location
to	O
test	O
positive	O
for	O
EVD	S-Disease
when	O
she	O
crossed	O
from	O
the	O
DRC	S-Location
into	O
the	O
district	O
of	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
an	O
almost	O
20-fold	O
higher	O
mortality	O
in	O
some	O
countries	O
in	O
the	O
Americas	S-Location
than	O
in	O
.	O
The	O
model	O
attributed	O
148,000–249,000	O
respiratory	O
deaths	O
to	O
influenza	O
in	O
an	O
average	O
pre-pandemic	O
season	O
,	O
with	O
only	O
19%	O
in	O
persons	O
&lt;65	O
years	O
of	O
age	O
.	O

Bayles	S-Person
said	O
the	O
Los	B-Location
Alamos	E-Location
program	O
would	O
complement	O
an	O
existing	O
educational	O
pipeline	O
previously	O
established	O
between	O
other	O
Department	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Defense	E-Organization
laboratories	O
,	O
UNMC	S-Organization
and	O
the	O
University	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Nebraska	E-Organization
at	O
.	O

It	O
and	O
several	O
others	O
across	O
the	O
country	O
are	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
$7	O
billion	O
Strategic	B-Platform
National	I-Platform
Stockpile	E-Platform
a	O
government	O
repository	O
of	O
drugs	O
and	O
supplies	O
ready	O
for	O
deployment	O
in	O
a	O
bioterrorism	O
or	O
nuclear	O
attack	O
,	O
or	O
against	O
an	O
infectious	O
disease	O
outbreak	O
-	O
of	O
either	O
a	O
known	O
pathogen	O
or	O
some	O
unknown	O
threat	O
with	O
pandemic	O
potential	O
,	O
which	O
global	O
health	O
officials	O
dub	O
"	O
Disease	O
X	O
"	O
-	O
or	O
other	O
major	O
public	O
health	O
emergency	O
.	O

NBIC	S-Organization
acts	O
as	O
a	O
hub	O
where	O
different	O
components	O
can	O
plan	O
and	O
coordinate	O
responses	O
to	O
biothreats	O
.	O

On	O
9	O
June	O
,	O
the	O
flare-up	O
was	O
declared	O
over	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
country	O
Ebola	S-Disease
-free	O
,	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
passage	O
of	O
the	O
42-day	O
period	O
;	O
Liberia	S-Location
then	O
entered	O
a	O
90-day	O
period	O
of	O
heightened	O
surveillance	O
,	O
which	O
ended	O
on	O
7	O
September	O
2016	O
.	O

More	O
typically	O
,	O
the	O
surgical	O
procedure	O
is	O
temporarily	O
interrupted	O
so	O
that	O
can	O
assess	O
the	O
success	O
of	O
the	O
procedure	O
or	O
guide	O
subsequent	O
surgical	O
work	O
.	O

Symptoms	O
usually	O
last	O
4–6	O
days	O
.	O

The	O
CDC	S-Organization
defines	O
four	O
biosafety	O
levels	O
for	O
activities	O
involving	O
infectious	O
disease	O
work	O
with	O
experimental	O
animals	O
.	O

European	B-Organization
Commission-Public	I-Organization
Health	I-Organization
EU	I-Organization
coordination	E-Organization
on	O
.	O

Since	O
then	O
,	O
it	O
has	O
jumped	O
from	O
radical	O
personal	O
experimentation	O
to	O
TED	O
st	S-Organization
to	O
everyday	O
lifestyle	O
products	O
,	O
including	O
coffee	O
.	O

We	O
report	O
isolation	O
of	O
a	O
New	B-Location
Delhi	E-Location
metallo-β-lactamase-5–producing	O
carbapenem-resistant	B-Pathogen
Escherichia	I-Pathogen
coli	I-Pathogen
sequence	E-Pathogen
type	O
167	O
from	O
companion	O
animals	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
.	O
Reports	O
of	O
in	O
companion	O
animals	O
are	O
rare	O
.	O

The	O
has	O
stated	O
that	O
the	O
reported	O
numbers	O
"	O
vastly	O
underestimate	O
the	O
magnitude	O
of	O
the	O
outbreak"	O
,	O
estimating	O
there	O
may	O
be	O
three	O
times	O
as	O
many	O
cases	O
as	O
officially	O
reported.Note	O
3:	O
Date	O
is	O
the	O
"	O
as	O
of	O
"	O
date	O
from	O
the	O
reference	O
.	O

Thereafter	O
,	O
confronted	O
by	O
the	O
selection	O
pressures	O
of	O
population	O
immunity	O
,	O
these	O
pandemic	O
viruses	O
begin	O
to	O
drift	O
genetically	O
and	O
eventually	O
settle	O
into	O
a	O
pattern	O
of	O
annual	O
epidemic	O
recurrences	O
caused	O
by	O
the	O
drifted	O
virus	O
variants	O
.	O

The	O
OECD	S-Organization
study	O
already	O
emphasized	O
the	O
need	O
for	O
development	O
and	O
maintenance	O
of	O
data	O
management	O
systems	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
build	O
up	O
and	O
secure	O
a	O
stable	O
data	O
management	O
infrastructure	O
.	O

"	O
It	O
has	O
always	O
been	O
a	O
personal	O
priority	O
to	O
increase	O
care	O
access	O
for	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Army	O
,	O
Navy	O
,	O
Air	O
Force	S-Organization
Marines	S-Organization
,	O
and	O
Coast	B-Organization
Guard	E-Organization
,	O
"	O
said	O
Joel	B-Person
Barthelemy	E-Person
,	O
CEO	O
of	O
GlobalMed	S-Organization
and	O
a	O
Marine	O
Corps	O
Reserve	O
Veteran.	O
"	O
The	O
Department	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Defense	E-Organization
is	O
a	O
huge	O
healthcare	O
provider	O
and	O
network	O
security	O
is	O
a	O
high	O
priority.	O
is	O
focused	O
on	O
every	O
aspect	O
of	O
security	O
and	O
compliance	O
throughout	O
our	O
vertically	O
integrated	O
software	O
applications	O
.	O

CT	S-Technology
data	O
sets	O
have	O
a	O
very	O
high	O
dynamic	O
range	O
which	O
must	O
be	O
reduced	O
for	O
display	O
or	O
printing	O
.	O

At	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
in	O
September	O
1985	O
,	O
Rajneesh	S-Person
accused	O
several	O
of	O
his	O
followers	O
of	O
participation	O
in	O
this	O
and	O
other	O
crimes	O
,	O
including	O
an	O
aborted	O
plan	O
in	O
1985	O
to	O
assassinate	O
a	O
United	O
States	O
Attorney	O
,	O
and	O
he	O
asked	O
state	O
and	O
federal	O
authorities	O
to	O
investigate	O
.	O

As	O
most	O
large-scale	O
projects	O
are	O
expected	O
to	O
use	O
a	O
large	O
diversity	O
of	O
'omics'	O
data	O
,	O
systems	O
should	O
be	O
flexible	O
to	O
incorporate	O
as	O
much	O
'omics'	O
data	O
as	O
possible	O
via	O
mechanisms	O
to	O
integrate	O
the	O
specific	O
standard	O
formats	O
,	O
e.g.	O
the	O
SysMO-SEEK	S-Platform
Just	O
Enough	O
Results	O
Model	O
(JERM)	O
templates	O
(see	O
'	O
SysMO-SEEK	S-Platform
'	O
section)	O
.	O

The	O
leaders	O
pledged	O
to	O
assist	O
in	O
carrying	O
out	O
WHO	S-Organization
regulations	O
.	O

Other	O
nations	O
,	O
notably	O
France	O
and	O
Japan	O
,	O
had	O
begun	O
their	O
own	O
biological-weapons	O
programs	O
.	O

Although	O
the	O
pandemic	O
mortality	O
estimate	O
was	O
similar	O
in	O
magnitude	O
to	O
that	O
of	O
seasonal	B-Disease
influenza	E-Disease
,	O
a	O
marked	O
shift	O
toward	O
mortality	O
among	O
persons	O
less	O
than	O
65	O
years	O
of	O
age	O
occurred	O
,	O
so	O
that	O
many	O
more	O
life-years	O
were	O
lost	O
.	O

On	O
11	O
June	O
2019	O
,	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
reported	O
that	O
the	O
virus	O
had	O
spread	O
to	O
Uganda	S-Location
.	O
A	O
5-year-old	O
Congolese	O
boy	O
entered	O
Uganda	S-Location
on	O
the	O
previous	O
Sunday	O
with	O
his	O
family	O
to	O
seek	O
medical	O
care	O
.	O

The	O
World	B-Organization
Health	I-Organization
Organization	E-Organization
attributes	O
human	O
error	O
and	O
poor	O
technique	O
as	O
the	O
primary	O
cause	O
of	O
.	O

Thus	O
,	O
they	O
could	O
open	O
the	O
survey	O
,	O
agree	O
to	O
the	O
human	O
ethics	O
considerations	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
view	O
the	O
remaining	O
questions	O
.	O

The	O
commune	O
leadership	O
planned	O
to	O
sicken	O
and	O
incapacitate	O
voters	O
in	O
The	O
Dalles	S-Location
where	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
voters	O
resided	O
,	O
to	O
sway	O
the	O
election	O
.	O

Nancy	B-Person
Cox	E-Person
,	O
head	O
of	O
the	O
,	O
has	O
said	O
,	O
"	O
This	O
particular	O
paper	O
is	O
extremely	O
interesting	O
because	O
it	O
demonstrates	O
for	O
the	O
first	O
time	O
what	O
we	O
had	O
worried	O
about	O
at	O
the	O
very	O
onset	O
of	O
the	O
pandemic	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
is	O
that	O
this	O
particular	O
virus	O
,	O
when	O
introduced	O
into	O
pigs	O
,	O
could	O
reassort	O
with	O
the	O
resident	O
viruses	O
in	O
pigs	O
and	O
we	O
would	O
have	O
new	O
gene	O
constellations	O
.	O

In	O
addition	O
,	O
the	O
network	O
has	O
a	O
steering	O
committee	O
,	O
which	O
consists	O
of	O
members	O
who	O
have	O
authority	O
to	O
influence	O
the	O
work	O
in	O
each	O
agency	O
and	O
which	O
is	O
responsible	O
for	O
coordinating	O
the	O
network	O
and	O
ensuring	O
a	O
balance	O
in	O
the	O
type	O
of	O
projects	O
run	O
.	O

Just	O
as	O
DARPA	S-Organization
's	O
mission	O
is	O
to	O
devise	O
emerging	O
technologies	O
for	O
the	O
military	O
,	O
a	O
similar	O
organization	O
could	O
be	O
created	O
for	O
,	O
as	O
an	O
example	O
,	O
to	O
develop	O
diagnostic	O
tools	O
for	O
the	O
health	O
market	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
.	O

But	O
the	O
screening	O
methods	O
are	O
imperfect	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
only	O
cover	O
about	O
80%	O
of	O
orders	O
.	O

His	O
followers	O
believed	O
he	O
was	O
involved	O
in	O
every	O
important	O
decision	O
that	O
Sheela	S-Person
made	O
,	O
but	O
those	O
allegations	O
were	O
never	O
proven.	O
"	O
Rajneesh	S-Person
insisted	O
that	O
,	O
who	O
he	O
said	O
was	O
his	O
only	O
source	O
of	O
information	O
during	O
his	O
period	O
of	O
isolation	O
,	O
used	O
her	O
position	O
to	O
impose	O
"	O
a	O
fascist	O
state	O
"	O
on	O
the	O
commune	O
.	O

Forty	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
on	O
April	O
2nd	O
,	O
1979	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
a	O
major	O
leak	O
of	O
deadly	O
anthrax	S-Pathogen
spores	O
from	O
the	O
Soviet	S-Organization
biological	O
warfare	O
facility	O
at	O
Military	B-Organization
Compound	I-Organization
19	E-Organization
on	O
the	O
edge	O
of	O
Sverdlovsk	S-Location
.	O
The	O
strain	O
of	O
the	O
pathogen	O
,	O
,	O
was	O
the	O
deadliest	O
.	O

The	O
technology	O
industry	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
has	O
warned	O
of	O
delays	O
to	O
shipments	O
of	O
electronic	O
goods	O
.	O

These	O
include	O
the	O
agents	O
that	O
cause	O
the	O
Spanish	B-Pathogen
flu	E-Pathogen
smallpox	S-Pathogen
,	O
Sars	S-Pathogen
and	O
H5N1	S-Pathogen
or	O
.	O
And	O
a	O
small	O
part	O
of	O
this	O
research	O
involves	O
making	O
strains	O
of	O
these	O
pathogens	O
that	O
pose	O
even	O
more	O
danger	O
than	O
the	O
natural	O
types	O
,	O
increasing	O
their	O
transmissibility	O
,	O
lethality	O
or	O
resistance	O
to	O
vaccination	O
or	O
treatment	O
.	O

Prime	O
Minister	O
,	O
Head	O
of	O
Government	O
,	O
Philemon	B-Person
Yang	E-Person
chaired	O
the	O
inauguration	O
ceremony	O
of	O
the	O
Centre	O
that	O
is	O
yet	O
another	O
fruit	O
of	O
the	O
Cameroon	S-Organization
-	O
USA	S-Organization
health	O
cooperation	O
.	O

None	O
of	O
these	O
viral	O
descendants	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
approaches	O
the	O
pathogenicity	O
of	O
the	O
1918	O
parent	O
virus	O
.	O

The	O
cysts	O
were	O
capable	O
of	O
reaching	O
macroscopic	O
dimensions	O
,	O
up	O
to	O
one	O
centimeter	O
in	O
diameter	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
later	O
findings	O
suggested	O
that	O
there	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
several	O
previous	O
cases	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
reported	O
that	O
pigs	O
in	O
the	O
village	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
infected	O
with	O
Ebola	S-Disease
some	O
time	O
before	O
the	O
first	O
human	O
case	O
occurred	O
.	O

BASE	S-Platform
supports	O
the	O
most	O
popular	O
microarray	O
platforms	O
and	O
provides	O
data	O
analysis	O
functionality	O
amended	O
by	O
a	O
plug-in	O
system	O
which	O
also	O
allows	O
straightforward	O
integration	O
of	O
other	O
systems-like	O
in	O
'	O
XperimentR	S-Platform
'	O
section	O
.	O

Government	O
actions	O
in	O
the	O
early	O
stages	O
of	O
the	O
virus'	O
arrival	O
in	O
the	O
country	O
in	O
September	O
1918	O
are	O
believed	O
to	O
have	O
unintentionally	O
accelerated	O
its	O
spread	O
throughout	O
the	O
country	O
.	O

For	O
each	O
biosafety	O
level	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
specific	O
supervisory	O
qualifications	O
as	O
assurance	O
that	O
laboratory	O
workers	O
are	O
provided	O
appropriate	O
role	O
models	O
and	O
knowledgeable	O
mentors	O
.	O

These	O
biological	O
agents	O
are	O
lowering	O
the	O
political	O
threshold	O
for	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
biological	O
weapons	O
and	O
are	O
likely	O
to	O
have	O
tremendous	O
environmental	O
and	O
health	O
impacts	O
.	O

It	O
appoints	O
the	O
Director-General	O
every	O
five	O
years	O
and	O
votes	O
on	O
matters	O
of	O
policy	O
and	O
finance	O
of	O
WHO	S-Organization
,	O
including	O
the	O
proposed	O
budget	O
.	O

On	O
7	O
May	O
2009	O
,	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
stated	O
that	O
containment	O
was	O
not	O
feasible	O
and	O
that	O
countries	O
should	O
focus	O
on	O
mitigating	O
the	O
effect	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
.	O

Retrieved	O
January	O
7	O
,	O
2009	O
.	O

On	O
24	O
April	O
,	O
the	O
Hong	B-Organization
Kong	I-Organization
Government	E-Organization
announced	O
an	O
HK$11.8 billion	O
relief	O
package	O
designed	O
to	O
assist	O
's	O
battered	O
tourism	O
,	O
entertainment	O
,	O
retail	O
,	O
and	O
catering	O
sectors	O
,	O
consisting	O
of	O
a	O
waiver	O
of	O
tourism-	O
and	O
transport-related	O
license	O
fees	O
,	O
and	O
HK$1 billion	O
allocated	O
for	O
tourism	O
promotion	O
overseas	O
.	O

By	O
contrast	O
,	O
the	O
DARPA	S-Organization
project	O
uses	O
"	O
horizontal	O
environmental	O
genetic	O
alteration	O
agents,	O
"	O
in	O
which	O
common	O
pests	O
are	O
the	O
agents	O
of	O
genetic	B-Technology
modification	E-Technology
.	O
The	O
insects	O
deliver	O
engineered	O
viruses	O
that	O
can	O
the	O
chromosomes	O
of	O
mature	O
plants	O
for	O
the	O
purpose	O
of	O
making	O
them	O
more	O
resistant	O
to	O
disease	O
and	O
drought	O
.	O

OSHA	S-Organization
Web	O
site	O
.	O

TOM	B-Person
FRIEDEN	E-Person
I	O
will	O
say	O
that	O
I'm	O
just	O
astonished	O
that	O
this	O
could	O
have	O
happened	O
here	O
.	O

Some	O
countries	O
have	O
passed	O
emergency	O
legislation	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
the	O
pandemic	O
.	O

The	O
billionaire	O
tech	O
investor	O
has	O
expressed	O
keen	O
interest	O
.	O

It	O
doesn't	O
matter	O
whether	O
this	O
is	O
from	O
insufficient	O
standards	O
,	O
inspections	O
,	O
operations	O
or	O
penalties	O
.	O

Senator	O
Jeff	B-Person
Sessions	E-Person
'	O
aide	O
on	O
Capitol	B-Location
Hill	E-Location
–	O
Watson	B-Person
Donald	E-Person
,	O
is	O
now	O
a	O
Senior	O
Director	O
at	O
.	O

The	O
first	O
is	O
the	O
"	O
small	O
molecule	O
"	O
approach	O
,	O
which	O
often	O
focuses	O
on	O
dietary	O
supplements	O
.	O

Nevertheless	O
,	O
undergraduates	O
in	O
biotechnology	O
and	O
medical	O
science	O
laboratories	O
at	O
Hadassah	B-Organization
Academic	I-Organization
College	E-Organization
in	O
Jerusalem	S-Location
take	O
this	O
lab	O
as	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
mandatory	O
curriculum	O
.	O

The	O
introduction	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
to	O
South	B-Location
America	E-Location
was	O
largely	O
related	O
to	O
international	O
travel	O
by	O
the	O
more	O
affluent	O
.	O

In	O
fact	O
,	O
the	O
project	O
that	O
led	O
to	O
the	O
potential	O
exposure	O
was	O
a	O
project	O
to	O
try	O
to	O
figure	O
out	O
a	O
quicker	O
way	O
to	O
diagnose	O
anthrax	S-Pathogen
with	O
a	O
new	O
and	O
interesting	O
technology	O
.	O

"	O
The	O
newly	O
developed	O
petrocalin	S-Drug
captures	O
petrobactin	O
,	O
thereby	O
depriving	O
the	O
anthrax	S-Pathogen
pathogen	O
of	O
access	O
to	O
vital	O
iron	O
and	O
acting	O
as	O
a	O
protein	O
antibiotic,	O
"	O
says	O
Skerra	S-Person
.	O
"	O
In	O
collaboration	O
with	O
professor	O
Siegfried	B-Person
Scherer	E-Person
from	O
the	O
,	O
we	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
that	O
this	O
approach	O
works	O
in	O
bacterial	O
cultures.	O
"	O

Historically	O
,	O
governments	O
and	O
authorities	O
have	O
relied	O
on	O
quarantines	O
to	O
protect	O
their	O
populations	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
a	O
United	B-Organization
Nations	I-Organization
Economic	I-Organization
Commission	I-Organization
for	I-Organization
Latin	I-Organization
America	E-Organization
estimate	O
,	O
the	O
pandemic-induced	O
recession	O
could	O
leave	O
14–22 million	O
more	O
people	O
in	O
extreme	O
poverty	O
in	O
than	O
would	O
have	O
been	O
in	O
that	O
situation	O
without	O
the	O
pandemic	O
.	O

He	O
added	O
that	O
the	O
scientists	O
were	O
"	O
jumping	O
to	O
far-reaching	O
conclusions	O
with	O
scant	O
information.	O
"	O

This	O
report	O
focuses	O
specifically	O
on	O
data	O
assets	O
identified	O
by	O
the	O
agencies	O
as	O
having	O
high	O
value	O
and	O
that	O
are	O
restricted	O
or	O
nonpublic	O
.	O

In	O
Europe	S-Location
disease	O
surveillance	O
is	O
beginning	O
to	O
be	O
organized	O
on	O
the	O
continent-wide	O
scale	O
needed	O
to	O
track	O
a	O
biological	O
emergency	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
few	O
hours	O
,	O
someone	O
found	O
that	O
the	O
filter	S-Equipment
was	O
missing	O
and	O
reinstalled	O
it	O
.	O

Rosenberg	S-Person
told	O
in	O
2016	O
,	O
"	O
Right	O
now	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
nothing	O
stopping	O
them	O
from	O
addressing	O
this	O
life-and-death	O
national	O
problem.	O
"	O

As	O
another	O
caller	O
said	O
,	O
this	O
is	O
the	O
envy	O
of	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

Prior	O
to	O
arrival	O
in	O
Sierra	B-Location
Leone	E-Location
a	O
set	O
of	O
laboratory	O
management	O
and	O
program	O
documents	O
were	O
prepared	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
BSL-3	S-Platform
documents	O
of	O
the	O
NIVDC	S-Organization
,	O
China	B-Organization
CDC	E-Organization
.	O
Those	O
documents	O
were	O
revised	O
after	O
we	O
arrived	O
at	O
the	O
SLE–CHN	B-Organization
Biosafety	I-Organization
Lab	E-Organization
,	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
acute	O
situation	O
.	O

The	O
Indonesian	B-Organization
government	E-Organization
also	O
halted	O
the	O
importation	O
of	O
pigs	O
and	O
initiated	O
the	O
examination	O
of	O
pigs	O
in	O
Indonesia	S-Location
.	O
The	O
Egyptian	B-Organization
government	E-Organization
ordered	O
the	O
slaughter	O
of	O
all	O
pigs	O
in	O
on	O
29	O
April	O
.	O

Dr	O
.	O

Cutting-edge	O
tools	O
like	O
CRISPR/Cas9	S-Technology
and	O
DNA	O
synthesis	O
raise	O
important	O
ethical	O
questions	O
that	O
are	O
increasingly	O
urgent	O
to	O
answer	O
.	O

In	O
2005	O
,	O
the	O
Oregon	B-Organization
State	I-Organization
Land	I-Organization
Board	E-Organization
agreed	O
to	O
sell	O
of	O
Wasco	B-Location
County	E-Location
,	O
including	O
Rajneeshpuram	S-Location
,	O
to	O
the	O
Colorado-based	O
youth	O
ministry	O
Young	O
Life	O
.	O

Anthrax	S-Disease
is	O
a	O
disease	O
caused	O
by	O
bacteria	O
.	O

Is	O
your	O
work	O
in	O
creating	B-Technology
a	I-Technology
synthetic	I-Technology
bacterial	I-Technology
cell	E-Technology
"	O
creating	O
life	O
from	O
scratch"?	O

The	O
DMMSS	S-Scientific_research_project
program	O
has	O
begun	O
roll-to-roll	O
development	O
,	O
creating	O
samples	O
up	O
to	O
eight	O
inches	O
wide	O
.	O

Any	O
improperly	O
performed	O
operations	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
acceptance	O
of	O
specimens	O
to	O
PCR	S-Equipment
preparation	O
,	O
will	O
result	O
in	O
the	O
possibility	O
of	O
EVD	B-Incident
laboratory	I-Incident
infection	I-Incident
or	I-Incident
environmental	I-Incident
contamination	I-Incident
with	I-Incident
EBOV	I-Incident
RNA	E-Incident
,	O
making	O
test	O
results	O
unreliable	O
.	O

Although	O
gadolinium	O
agents	O
have	O
proved	O
useful	O
for	O
patients	O
with	O
renal	B-Disease
impairment	E-Disease
in	O
patients	O
with	O
severe	O
renal	B-Disease
failure	E-Disease
requiring	O
dialysis	S-Technology
there	O
is	O
a	O
risk	O
of	O
a	O
rare	O
but	O
serious	O
illness	O
,	O
nephrogenic	B-Disease
systemic	I-Disease
fibrosis	E-Disease
,	O
which	O
may	O
be	O
linked	O
to	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
certain	O
gadolinium-containing	O
agents	O
.	O

Biohacking	O
is	O
a	O
concept	O
that	O
gained	O
currency	O
in	O
popular	O
culture	O
over	O
the	O
past	O
decade	O
,	O
initially	O
as	O
an	O
apparently	O
earnest	O
approach	O
to	O
applying	O
the	O
tech-hacker	O
ethos	O
to	O
biology	O
.	O

The	O
salmonellosis	O
outbreak	O
was	O
also	O
discussed	O
in	O
the	O
media	O
within	O
the	O
context	O
of	O
the	O
.	O

Rickettsia	B-Pathogen
prowazekii	E-Pathogen
,	O
Coxiella	B-Pathogen
burnetii	E-Pathogen
were	O
listed	O
in	O
the	O
highest	O
threat	O
group	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
Russian	O
biodefense	O
categorization	O
,	O
but	O
was	O
included	O
in	O
the	O
second	O
highest	O
category	O
by	O
the	O
US	B-Organization
CDC	E-Organization
and	O
the	O
EU	S-Location
.	O
Influenza	O
virus	O
was	O
listed	O
in	O
the	O
highest	O
threat	O
group	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
Russian	O
biodefense	O
categorization	O
,	O
but	O
was	O
included	O
in	O
the	O
second	O
highest	O
category	O
by	O
the	O
EU	S-Location
,	O
and	O
was	O
not	O
specifically	O
listed	O
by	O
.	O

These	O
could	O
arm	O
warheads	O
for	O
their	O
SS-18	O
intercontinental	O
missiles	O
to	O
target	O
American	O
cities	O
.	O

The	O
M33's	O
sub-munition	O
,	O
the	O
pipe-bomb-like	O
cylindrical	O
M114	O
bomb	O
,	O
was	O
also	O
completed	O
and	O
battle-ready	O
by	O
1952	O
.	O

A	O
40-year-old	O
woman	O
became	O
the	O
first	O
local	O
case	O
in	O
Shanghai	S-Location
.	O
A	O
Chinese	O
health	O
specialist	O
admitted	O
at	O
a	O
press	O
conference	O
of	O
not	O
informing	O
the	O
public	O
early	O
enough	O
about	O
the	O
outbreak	O
.	O

Other	O
studies	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
induce	O
transcription	O
of	O
Cas9	O
with	O
a	O
small	O
molecule	O
,	O
doxycycline	O
.	O

Bavarian	B-Organization
Nordic	E-Organization
partnered	O
with	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organization
Biomedical	I-Organization
Advanced	I-Organization
Research	I-Organization
and	I-Organization
Development	I-Organization
Authority	E-Organization
to	O
stockpile	O
Imvamune	S-Vaccine
,	O
a	O
smallpox	B-Vaccine
vaccine	E-Vaccine
to	O
protect	O
66	O
million	O
Americans	O
,	O
many	O
of	O
whom	O
have	O
weakened	O
immune	O
systems	O
and	O
do	O
not	O
respond	O
well	O
to	O
drugs	O
for	O
the	O
treatment	O
of	O
smallpox	S-Disease
currently	O
in	O
the	O
stockpile	O
.	O

That	O
means	O
that	O
a	O
big	O
amount	O
of	O
cartilage	O
and	O
a	O
thin	O
layer	O
of	O
compact	O
bone	O
can	O
cause	O
the	O
same	O
attenuation	O
in	O
a	O
voxel	O
as	O
hyperdense	O
cartilage	O
alone	O
.	O

Such	O
procedures	O
use	O
no	O
ferromagnetic	O
instruments	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
US	S-Location
,	O
it	O
can	O
take	O
10	O
years	O
for	O
a	O
new	O
drug	O
to	O
be	O
developed	O
and	O
approved	O
;	O
for	O
people	O
with	O
serious	O
health	O
conditions	O
,	O
that	O
wait	O
time	O
can	O
feel	O
cruelly	O
long.	O
claims	O
that's	O
part	O
of	O
why	O
he	O
wants	O
to	O
democratize	O
science	O
and	O
empower	O
people	O
to	O
experiment	O
on	O
themselves	O
.	O

The	O
peak	O
of	O
U.S.	S-Location
biological	O
weapons	O
delivery	O
system	O
development	O
came	O
during	O
the	O
1960s	O
.	O

The	O
mid-level	O
in	O
this	O
range	O
is	O
about	O
61 million	O
people	O
infected	O
with	O
.	O

If	O
initial	O
data	O
from	O
ZIK-101	S-Drug
are	O
supportive	O
,	O
will	O
work	O
to	O
progress	O
into	O
Phase	O
2	O
development	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
possible	O
.	O

Ribosome	O
splitting	O
and	O
recycling:	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
drug-mediated	O
stalling	O
of	O
the	O
ribosome	O
by	O
lincomycin	S-Drug
and	O
erythromycin	S-Drug
unstalled	O
by	O
a	O
heat	O
shock	O
protein	O
found	O
in	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
an	O
homologous	O
of	O
HflX	O
from	O
other	O
bacteria	O
.	O

The	O
experiments	O
date	O
back	O
to	O
2007	O
when	O
an	O
unspecified	O
quantity	O
of	O
the	O
toxin	O
was	O
procured	O
to	O
the	O
Department	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
the	I-Organization
Army	E-Organization
by	O
the	O
same	O
company	O
–	O
.	O

Richard	B-Person
Preston	E-Person
tells	O
the	O
story	O
of	O
Sverdlovsk	S-Location
in	O
the	O
chapter	O
'	O
Invisible	B-Document
History	I-Document
(II)	E-Document
'	O
from	O
his	O
book	O
.	O

In	O
general	O
,	O
the	O
grade	O
order	O
of	O
most	O
biological	O
agents	O
of	O
laboratory	B-Document
biosafety	I-Document
category	I-Document
list	E-Document
and	O
biodefense	B-Document
category	I-Document
lists	E-Document
was	O
found	O
to	O
be	O
consistent	O
.	O

These	O
bombs	O
enabled	O
Japanese	O
soldiers	O
to	O
launch	O
biological	O
attacks	O
,	O
infecting	O
agriculture	O
,	O
reservoirs	O
,	O
wells	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
other	O
areas	O
with	O
anthrax	S-Pathogen
plague-carrier	B-Pathogen
fleas	E-Pathogen
,	O
typhoid	S-Pathogen
,	O
dysentery	S-Pathogen
,	O
cholera	S-Pathogen
or	O
other	O
deadly	O
pathogens	O
.	O

On	O
25	O
September	O
,	O
Peter	B-Person
Salama	E-Person
of	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
indicated	O
that	O
insecurity	O
is	O
obstructing	O
efforts	O
to	O
stop	O
the	O
virus	O
and	O
believed	O
a	O
combination	O
of	O
factors	O
could	O
establish	O
conditions	O
for	O
an	O
epidemic	O
.	O

DAD	S-Phenotype
	S-Phenotype
is	O
the	O
cause	O
of	O
acute	B-Disease
respiratory	I-Disease
distress	I-Disease
syndrome	E-Disease
()	O
and	O
severe	O
hypoxemia	O
.	O

Group	O
4	O
causes	O
severe	O
disease	O
and	O
is	O
defined	O
by	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
,	O
NIH	S-Organization
and	O
EU	S-Location
as	O
agents	O
for	O
which	O
no	O
effective	O
treatments	O
or	O
preventive	O
measures	O
are	O
available	O
.	O

Although	O
most	O
cases	O
are	O
mild	O
,	O
these	O
epidemics	O
still	O
cause	O
severe	O
illness	O
in	O
people	O
and	O
290,000–650,000	O
deaths	O
worldwide	O
every	O
year	O
.	O

Once	O
the	O
full	O
suspension	O
is	O
lifted	O
,	O
the	O
CDC	S-Organization
will	O
resume	O
inspections	O
on	O
a	O
regulatory	O
basis	O
as	O
mandated	O
by	O
the	O
federal	O
regulations	O
.	O

As	O
scientists	O
improve	O
their	O
ability	O
to	O
read	O
and	O
write	O
DNA	O
,	O
the	O
possibilities	O
continue	O
to	O
expand	O
.	O

1	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
studies	O
conducted	O
in	O
Australia	S-Location
and	O
Japan	S-Location
,	O
screening	O
individuals	O
for	O
influenza	O
symptoms	O
at	O
airports	O
during	O
the	O
was	O
not	O
an	O
effective	O
method	O
of	O
infection	O
control	O
.	O

Within	O
the	O
division	O
are	O
two	O
programs:	O
the	O
Federal	B-Document
Select	I-Document
Agent	I-Document
Program	E-Document
(	O
FSAP	S-Document
)	O
and	O
the	O
Import	B-Document
Permit	I-Document
Program	E-Document
.	O
The	O
FSAP	S-Document
is	O
run	O
jointly	O
with	O
an	O
office	O
within	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organization
Department	I-Organization
of	I-Organization
Agriculture	E-Organization
,	O
regulating	O
agents	O
that	O
can	O
cause	O
disease	O
in	O
humans	O
,	O
animals	O
,	O
and	O
plants.	O
regulates	O
the	O
importation	O
of	O
"	O
infectious	O
biological	O
materials.	O
"	O

In	O
June	O
2010	O
,	O
scientists	O
from	O
Hong	B-Location
Kong	E-Location
reported	O
discovery	O
of	O
a	O
new	O
swine	B-Pathogen
flu	I-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
:	O
a	O
hybrid	O
of	O
the	O
pandemic	O
H1N1	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
and	O
viruses	O
previously	O
found	O
in	O
pigs	O
.	O

Synthetic	B-Organization
Genomics	I-Organization
Inc	E-Organization
(	O
SGI	S-Organization
)	O
is	O
a	O
privately	O
held	O
company	O
founded	O
to	O
apply	O
synthetic	O
genomic-driven	O
commercial	O
solutions	O
in	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
global	O
challenges	O
including	O
energy	O
and	O
the	O
environment	O
.	O

ASM	O
members	O
are	O
now	O
obligated	O
to	O
discourage	O
any	O
use	O
of	O
microbiology	O
contrary	O
to	O
the	O
welfare	O
of	O
humankind	O
,	O
including	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
microbes	O
as	O
biological	O
weapons	O
and	O
will	O
call	O
to	O
the	O
attention	O
of	O
the	O
public	O
or	O
the	O
appropriate	O
authorities	O
misuses	O
of	O
microbiology	O
or	O
of	O
information	O
derived	O
from	O
microbiology	O
.	O

A	O
scientist	O
at	O
Texas	B-Organization
A&amp;M	I-Organization
in	I-Organization
College	I-Organization
Station-B	E-Organization
yron	O
stuck	O
himself	O
with	O
a	O
needle	O
while	O
injecting	O
a	O
mouse	O
that	O
was	O
previously	O
infected	O
wit	O
h	B-Pathogen
a	I-Pathogen
recombinant	I-Pathogen
strain	I-Pathogen
of	I-Pathogen
Borrelia	I-Pathogen
burgdor	E-Pathogen
feri	O
,	O
the	O
bacteria	O
that	O
cauease	O
,	O
in	O
February	O
2014	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
interwar	O
period	O
,	O
little	O
research	O
was	O
done	O
in	O
biological	O
warfare	O
in	O
both	O
Britain	O
and	O
the	O
United	O
States	O
at	O
first	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
them	O
,	O
"	O
we've	O
now	O
seen	O
several	O
cases	O
that	O
don't	O
have	O
any	O
symptoms	O
at	O
all	O
,	O
asymptomatic	O
cases	O
.	O

That's	O
why	O
events	O
like	O
this	O
should	O
never	O
happen	O
,	O
and	O
that's	O
why	O
I	O
will	O
do	O
everything	O
in	O
my	O
power	O
to	O
make	O
sure	O
that	O
nothing	O
like	O
this	O
happens	O
again	O
.	O

G.P.O.	O
,	O
2012	O
.	O

On	O
Friday	O
,	O
30	O
March	O
1979	O
a	O
technician	O
removed	O
a	O
clogged	O
filter	S-Equipment
while	O
drying	O
machines	O
were	O
temporarily	O
turned	O
off	O
.	O

A	O
December	O
2009	O
study	O
found	O
that	O
the	O
transmissibility	O
of	O
the	O
in	O
households	O
is	O
lower	O
than	O
that	O
seen	O
in	O
past	O
pandemics	O
.	O

For	O
a	O
start	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
few	O
large-scale	O
pharmaceutical	O
campaigns	O
.	O

It's	O
because	O
it's	O
the	O
truth.	O
"	O

Eshoo	S-Person
said	O
she	O
looks	O
forward	O
to	O
swift	O
consideration	O
and	O
approval	O
of	O
H.R.	B-Document
6378	E-Document
by	O
members	O
in	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organization
Senate	E-Organization
"	O
so	O
that	O
it	O
can	O
be	O
signed	O
into	O
law	O
before	O
Sept.	O
30,	O
"	O
which	O
is	O
the	O
deadline	O
to	O
reauthorize	O
.	O

Then	O
,	O
around	O
the	O
1960s	O
,	O
most	O
likely	O
due	O
to	O
climate	O
change	O
or	O
human	O
activities	O
,	O
the	O
genetic	O
diversity	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
dropped	O
rapidly	O
and	O
most	O
lineages	O
became	O
extinct	O
.	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
19	O
(10%)	O
laboratories	O
had	O
a	O
hepatitis	B-Pathogen
B	I-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
vaccination	O
programme	O
,	O
5	O
(6.	O
2%)	O
applied	O
BCG	B-Vaccine
vaccine	E-Vaccine
,	O
and	O
2	O
(1.	O
1%0)	O
vaccinated	O
the	O
staff	O
against	O
.	O

A	O
visual	O
representation	O
of	O
the	O
raw	O
data	O
obtained	O
is	O
called	O
a	O
sinogram	O
,	O
yet	O
it	O
is	O
not	O
sufficient	O
for	O
interpretation	O
.	O

Shigella	S-Pathogen
in	O
particular	O
is	O
estimated	O
to	O
cause	O
80	O
–165	O
million	O
cases	O
of	O
disease	O
worldwide	O
,	O
resulting	O
in	O
600,000	O
deaths	O
annually	O
and	O
is	O
particularly	O
prevalent	O
in	O
both	O
sub-	O
Saharan	S-Location
Africa	S-Location
and	O
.	O

Allegations	O
were	O
made	O
that	O
a	O
"	O
chemical	O
section	O
"	O
of	O
a	O
US	S-Location
clandestine	O
unit	O
hidden	O
within	O
Yokosuka	B-Location
naval	I-Location
base	E-Location
was	O
operational	O
during	O
the	O
Korean	O
War	O
,	O
and	O
then	O
worked	O
on	O
unspecified	O
projects	O
inside	O
the	O
from	O
1955	O
to	O
1959	O
,	O
before	O
returning	O
to	O
Japan	O
to	O
enter	O
the	O
private	O
sector	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
one	O
medicine	O
available	O
that	O
is	O
not	O
very	O
effective	O
,	O
especially	O
when	O
people	O
don't	O
come	O
to	O
the	O
hospital	O
early	O
.	O

Also	O
,	O
systems	O
like	O
ISA	O
software	O
suite	O
,	O
BASE	S-Platform
(e.g.	O
with	O
XperimentR	S-Platform
)	O
,	O
DIPSBC	S-Platform
or	O
Gaggle	S-Platform
(e.g.	O
with	O
)	O
have	O
been	O
integrated	O
with	O
other	O
data	O
management	O
solutions	O
.	O

Downloaded	O
Oct.22	O
,	O
2017	O
.	O

The	O
cross-sectoral	O
FBD	S-Platform
network	O
not	O
only	O
adopts	O
to	O
the	O
One	O
Health	O
concept	O
;	O
it	O
also	O
leads	O
to	O
improved	O
coordination	O
and	O
harmonization	O
between	O
laboratories	O
that	O
undoubtedly	O
will	O
save	O
resources	O
and	O
strengthen	O
national	O
biopreparedness	O
.	O

Belgian	O
nuns	O
serving	O
the	O
community	O
were	O
also	O
infected	O
,	O
and	O
two	O
of	O
them	O
died	O
,	O
along	O
with	O
Mayinga	B-Person
N'Seka	E-Person
,	O
a	O
Zairean	O
nurse	O
,	O
after	O
the	O
group	O
was	O
transported	O
to	O
Kinshasa	S-Organization
.	O
With	O
assistance	O
from	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
,	O
the	O
outbreak	O
was	O
eventually	O
contained	O
by	O
quarantining	O
local	O
villagers	O
in	O
their	O
communities	O
,	O
sterilizing	O
medical	O
equipment	O
,	O
and	O
providing	O
protective	O
clothing	O
to	O
medical	O
personnel	O
.	O

During	O
the	O
closing	O
stages	O
of	O
the	O
Rhodesian	O
Bush	O
War	O
,	O
the	O
Rhodesian	O
government	O
resorted	O
to	O
use	O
chemical	O
and	O
biological	O
warfare	O
agents	O
.	O

Infectious	O
disease	O
preparedness	O
work	O
focuses	O
predominantly	O
on	O
an	O
historical	O
list	O
of	O
pathogens	O
derived	O
from	O
biological	O
warfare	O
agents	O
,	O
political	O
considerations	O
,	O
and	O
recent	O
outbreaks	O
.	O

"	O
Use	O
antibiotics	O
only	O
when	O
needed	O
,	O
especially	O
not	O
in	O
'just	O
in	O
case'	O
scenarios,	O
"	O
emphasized	O
Dr	O
.	O

The	O
3	O
recurrences	O
in	O
1889–1892	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
were	O
spread	O
over	O
&gt;3	O
years	O
,	O
in	O
contrast	O
to	O
1918–1919	O
,	O
when	O
the	O
sequential	O
waves	O
seen	O
in	O
individual	O
countries	O
were	O
typically	O
compressed	O
into	O
≈8–9	O
months	O
.	O

TOM	B-Person
FRIEDEN	E-Person
In	O
terms	O
of	O
the	O
impact	O
of	O
the	O
moratorium	O
,	O
we're	O
going	O
to	O
assess	O
that	O
laboratory	O
by	O
laboratory	O
.	O

Within	O
the	O
past	O
few	O
years	O
,	O
epigenetic	O
marks	O
in	O
different	O
human	O
cells	O
have	O
been	O
closely	O
researched	O
and	O
certain	O
patterns	O
within	O
the	O
marks	O
have	O
been	O
found	O
to	O
correlate	O
with	O
everything	O
ranging	O
from	O
tumor	O
growth	O
to	O
brain	O
activity	O
.	O

First	O
,	O
without	O
killing	O
the	O
bacteria	O
,	O
the	O
technology	O
must	O
extract	O
and	O
isolate	O
them	O
from	O
complex	O
environments	O
such	O
as	O
soil	O
,	O
runoff	O
,	O
sewage	O
,	O
biofilms	O
,	O
and	O
medical	O
samples	O
,	O
where	O
numerous	O
strains	O
of	O
bacteria	O
live	O
together	O
.	O

What's	O
distressing	O
about	O
it	O
are	O
two	O
things	O
,	O
really	O
.	O

between	O
about	O
195,000	O
and	O
403,000	O
H1N1	S-Pathogen
hospitalizations	O
occurred	O
between	O
April	O
2009	O
and	O
10	O
April	O
2010	O
.	O

That	O
includes	O
mechanical	O
paitents	O
built	O
specific	O
to	O
trauma	O
injuries	O
,	O
which	O
can	O
bleed	O
–	O
and	O
bleed	O
out	O
–	O
and	O
offer	O
more	O
options	O
for	O
surgical	O
procedures	O
.	O

A	O
covert	O
military	O
research	O
and	O
development	O
program	O
continued	O
for	O
another	O
four	O
years	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
intent	O
of	O
resuming	O
agent	O
production	O
and	O
weapons	O
manufacture	O
after	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
UN	S-Organization
sanctions	O
.	O

Please	O
see	O
Additional	O
file	O
1	O
for	O
translations	O
of	O
the	O
abstract	O
into	O
the	O
six	O
official	O
working	O
languages	O
of	O
the	O
United	B-Organization
Nations	E-Organization

On	O
28	O
May	O
2013	O
,	O
a	O
report	O
by	O
the	O
Associated	B-Organization
Press	E-Organization
said	O
a	O
French	O
patient	O
died	O
of	O
the	O
novel	O
coronavirus	O
related	O
to	O
.	O
Fifty	O
percent	O
of	O
those	O
infected	O
have	O
died	O
.	O

Similarly	O
,	O
immunodeficiency	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
and	O
were	O
categorized	O
according	O
to	O
the	O
highest	O
laboratory	O
biosafety	O
level	O
,	O
but	O
were	O
not	O
included	O
in	O
the	O
corresponding	O
biodefense	O
level	O
.	O

Like	O
the	O
VA	O
,	O
the	O
military's	O
health	O
facilities	O
cannot	O
accommodate	O
the	O
demand	O
for	O
care	O
by	O
all	O
active	O
duty	O
service	O
people	O
,	O
their	O
dependents	O
,	O
and	O
retirees	O
(many	O
of	O
whom	O
are	O
not	O
eligible	O
for	O
VA	O
services)	O
.	O

Once	O
the	O
program	O
begins	O
,	O
a	O
separate	O
independent	O
verification	O
and	O
validation	O
(IV&amp;V)	O
team	O
contractedARPA	O
will	O
work	O
with	O
performer	O
teams	O
to	O
provide	O
standardized	O
biological	O
samples	O
that	O
simulate	O
different	O
environments	O
and	O
include	O
mixtures	O
of	O
known	O
bacteria	O
.	O

Resistance	O
to	O
recently	O
developed	O
drugs	O
such	O
as	O
artemisinin	S-Drug
has	O
also	O
been	O
reported	O
.	O

On	O
9	O
April	O
2020	O
,	O
preliminary	O
results	O
found	O
that	O
15	O
percent	O
of	O
people	O
tested	O
in	O
Gangelt	S-Location
the	O
centre	O
of	O
a	O
major	O
infection	O
cluster	O
in	O
Germany	S-Location
,	O
tested	O
positive	O
for	O
antibodies	O
.	O

During	O
,	O
this	O
laboratory	O
did	O
phenomenal	O
work	O
sequencing	O
specimens	O
,	O
figuring	O
out	O
where	O
the	O
virus	O
was	O
going	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
giving	O
latitude	O
to	O
the	O
scientific	O
community	O
to	O
identify	O
which	O
pathogens	O
,	O
in	O
particular	O
,	O
labs	O
and	O
institutions	O
should	O
be	O
inventoried.	O
*How	O
is	O
this	O
enforceable*?	O
*What	O
are	O
the	O
consequences	O
for	O
non-compliance*?	O
In	O
short	O
,	O
its	O
not	O
enforceable	O
and	O
there	O
are	O
no	O
consequences	O
for	O
non-compliance	O
.	O

Along	O
with	O
laboratory	O
testing	O
,	O
chest	B-Technology
CT	I-Technology
scans	E-Technology
may	O
be	O
helpful	O
to	O
diagnose	O
in	O
individuals	O
with	O
a	O
high	O
clinical	O
suspicion	O
of	O
infection	O
but	O
are	O
not	O
recommended	O
for	O
routine	O
screening	O
.	O

Although	O
the	O
Japanese	O
effort	O
lacked	O
the	O
technological	O
sophistication	O
of	O
the	O
American	O
or	O
British	O
programs	O
,	O
it	O
far	O
outstripped	O
them	O
in	O
its	O
widespread	O
application	O
and	O
indiscriminate	O
brutality	O
.	O

Anthrax	S-Pathogen
is	O
of	O
course	O
the	O
first	O
choice	O
because	O
the	O
causative	O
agent	O
,	O
B.	B-Pathogen
anthracis	E-Pathogen
,	O
fulfils	O
nearly	O
all	O
of	O
these	O
specifications	O
(Fig.3)	O
.	O

It	O
spread	O
following	O
the	O
path	O
of	O
its	O
human	O
carriers	O
,	O
along	O
trade	O
routes	O
and	O
shipping	O
lines	O
.	O

First	O
,	O
can	O
the	O
bacteria	O
survive	O
and	O
establish	O
a	O
niche	O
in	O
a	O
host	O
organism?	O
Does	O
it	O
,	O
for	O
instance	O
,	O
adhere	O
to	O
the	O
host's	O
cell	O
membranes?	O
Second	O
,	O
can	O
the	O
bacteria	O
harm	O
its	O
host?	O
For	O
example	O
,	O
does	O
it	O
secrete	O
toxins	O
or	O
have	O
flagella	O
that	O
could	O
disrupt	O
the	O
host's	O
mucosal	O
tissue?	O
And	O
third	O
,	O
can	O
the	O
bacterium	O
protect	O
itself?	O
Does	O
it	O
inactivate	O
the	O
host's	O
protective	O
antibodies	O
or	O
resist	O
antibiotics?	O

The	O
updated	O
recommendations	O
were	O
based	O
on	O
preliminary	O
results	O
from	O
the	O
NIAID-ACTT	B-Scientific_research_project
study	E-Scientific_research_project
,	O
which	O
suggested	O
a	O
beneficial	O
effect	O
of	O
remdesivir	S-Drug
in	O
the	O
treatment	O
of	O
hospitalized	O
individuals	O
with	O
severe	O
.	O

Following	O
Nixon	S-Person
's	O
November	O
1969	O
order	O
,	O
scientists	O
at	O
Fort	B-Location
Detrick	E-Location
worked	O
on	O
one	O
toxin	O
,	O
Staphylococcus	B-Pathogen
enterotoxin	I-Pathogen
type	I-Pathogen
B	E-Pathogen
(	O
SEB	S-Pathogen
)	O
,	O
for	O
several	O
more	O
months	O
.	O

SGI	S-Organization
has	O
filed	O
13	O
patent	O
family	O
applications	O
on	O
the	O
unique	O
inventions	O
of	O
the	O
JCVI	S-Organization
team	O
.	O

When	O
categorized	O
into	O
types	O
,	O
most	O
of	O
the	O
initiatives	O
were	O
found	O
to	O
be	O
in	O
the	O
category	O
of	O
general	O
awareness	O
and	O
information	O
exchange	O
workshops	O
at	O
country	O
level	O
70.	O
68%	O
(n = 1295)	O
.	O

Yet	O
those	O
suits	O
ruptured	O
or	O
developed	O
holes	O
in	O
at	O
least	O
37	O
incidents	O
during	O
a	O
20-month	O
period	O
in	O
2013	O
and	O
2014	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
lab	O
incident	O
reports	O
obtained	O
by	O
USA	B-Organization
TODAY	E-Organization
under	O
the	O
federal	O
.	O

Dr	O
Paul	B-Person
Farmer	E-Person
stated:	O
"	O
Most	O
of	O
Ebola	S-Disease
's	O
victims	O
may	O
well	O
be	O
dying	O
from	O
other	O
causes:	O
women	O
in	O
childbirth	O
,	O
children	O
from	O
,	O
people	O
in	O
road	O
accidents	O
or	O
from	O
trauma	O
of	O
other	O
sorts.	O
"	O

All	O
told	O
,	O
since	O
President	O
urged	O
nations	O
to	O
contribute	O
to	O
the	O
response	O
,	O
countries	O
from	O
all	O
over	O
the	O
world	O
,	O
private	O
sector	O
stakeholders	O
,	O
international	O
organizations	O
,	O
and	O
multilateral	O
development	O
banks	O
have	O
pledged	O
more	O
than	O
$2	O
billion	O
to	O
end	O
the	O
epidemic	O
.	O

By	O
making	O
a	O
comparison	O
of	O
the	O
number	O
and	O
type	O
of	O
articles	O
published	O
by	O
Environmental	O
Biosafety	O
Research	O
(EBR)	O
with	O
those	O
from	O
other	O
journals	O
active	O
in	O
the	O
arena	O
of	O
GMO	S-Technology
biosafety	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
possible	O
to	O
shed	O
light	O
on	O
the	O
answer	O
to	O
the	O
question	O
posed	O
in	O
the	O
title	O
.	O

By	O
23	O
March	O
,	O
Iran	S-Location
was	O
experiencing	O
fifty	O
new	O
cases	O
every	O
hour	O
and	O
one	O
new	O
death	O
every	O
ten	O
minutes	O
due	O
to	O
coronavirus	S-Pathogen
.	O
According	O
to	O
a	O
WHO	S-Organization
official	O
,	O
there	O
may	O
be	O
five	O
times	O
more	O
cases	O
in	O
than	O
what	O
is	O
being	O
reported	O
.	O

Publication	O
S/1995/864	O
,	O
59.Zilinskas	O
,	O
R.A.	O
,	O
"	O
:	O
The	O
Past	O
as	O
Future?	O
"	O
,	O
Journal	O
of	O
the	O
American	O
Medical	O
Association	O
,	O
1997;278:418–424	O
,	O
60	O
.	O

Under	O
another	O
DTRA	S-Organization
project	O
"	O
Epidemiology	B-Scientific_research_project
and	I-Scientific_research_project
Ecology	I-Scientific_research_project
of	I-Scientific_research_project
Tularemia	I-Scientific_research_project
in	I-Scientific_research_project
Georgia	E-Scientific_research_project
"	O
(2013-2016)	O
6,148	O
ground	O
ticks	O
were	O
collected	O
;	O
5,871	O
were	O
collected	O
off	O
the	O
cattle	O
and	O
1,310	O
fleas	O
and	O
731	O
ticks	O
were	O
caught	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
medication	O
known	O
to	O
be	O
effective	O
at	O
preventing	O
COVID‑19	S-Disease
After	O
the	O
implementation	O
of	O
social	O
distancing	O
and	O
stay-at-home	O
orders	O
,	O
many	O
regions	O
have	O
been	O
able	O
to	O
sustain	O
an	O
effective	O
transmission	O
rate	O
("Rt")	O
of	O
less	O
than	O
one	O
,	O
meaning	O
the	O
disease	O
is	O
in	O
remission	O
in	O
those	O
areas	O
.	O

At	O
the	O
time	O
of	O
his	O
arrival	O
in	O
Japan	S-Location
he	O
had	O
no	O
knowledge	O
of	O
what	O
Unit	B-Organization
731	E-Organization
was	O
.	O

SECOA	S-International_exchange_and_cooperation
(	O
Solutions	B-International_exchange_and_cooperation
for	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Environmental	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Contrasts	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
in	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Coastal	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Areas	E-International_exchange_and_cooperation
)	O
is	O
a	O
multi-national	O
research	O
project	O
examining	O
the	O
effects	O
of	O
human	O
mobility	O
on	O
urban	O
settlements	O
in	O
fragile	O
coastal	O
environments	O
.	O

Based	O
on	O
many	O
years	O
of	O
experience	O
in	O
Africa	S-Location
several	O
months	O
working	O
in	O
the	O
present	O
epidemic-	O
MSF	S-Organization
took	O
a	O
conservative	O
approach	O
.	O

On	O
23	O
September	O
2014	O
,	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
revised	O
their	O
previous	O
projection	O
,	O
stating	O
that	O
they	O
expected	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
Ebola	S-Disease
cases	O
in	O
Western	B-Location
Africa	E-Location
to	O
be	O
in	O
excess	O
of	O
20,000	O
by	O
2	O
November	O
2014	O
.	O

Broad,	B-Person
W.J	E-Person
.	O
and	O
Miller	B-Person
J	E-Person
.	O
(2002)	O
,	O
"	O
Traces	O
of	O
Terror:	O
The	O
Bioterror	O
Threat	O
;	O
Report	O
Provides	O
New	O
Details	O
of	O
"	O
,	O
The	O
New	O
York	O
Times	O
;	O
15	O
June	O
issue	O
.	O

The	O
State	B-Organization
Department	E-Organization
closely	O
with	O
U.S.	S-Location
and	O
West	B-Location
African	E-Location
diplomats	O
on	O
the	O
ground	O
,	O
and	O
our	O
counterparts	O
throughout	O
the	O
government	O
to	O
bring	O
the	O
full	O
range	O
of	O
U.S.	S-Location
resources	O
to	O
bear	O
.	O

Analyses	O
of	O
the	O
genetic	O
sequences	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
isolates	O
,	O
promptly	O
shared	O
on	O
the	O
GISAID	B-Platform
database	E-Platform
according	O
to	O
Nature	S-Organization
and	O
WHO	S-Organization
,	O
soon	O
determined	O
that	O
the	O
strain	O
contains	O
genes	O
from	O
five	O
different	O
flu	O
viruses:	O
North	B-Disease
American	I-Disease
swine	I-Disease
influenza	E-Disease
,	O
North	B-Disease
American	I-Disease
avian	I-Disease
influenza	E-Disease
,	O
human	O
influenza	O
,	O
and	O
two	O
swine	O
influenza	O
viruses	O
typically	O
found	O
in	O
Asia	S-Location
and	O
Europe	S-Location
.	O
Further	O
analysis	O
has	O
shown	O
that	O
several	O
proteins	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
are	O
most	O
similar	O
to	O
strains	O
that	O
cause	O
mild	O
symptoms	O
in	O
humans	O
,	O
leading	O
virologist	O
to	O
suggest	O
on	O
1May	O
2009	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
initial	O
indications	O
are	O
that	O
the	O
virus	O
was	O
unlikely	O
to	O
cause	O
severe	O
symptoms	O
for	O
most	O
people	O
.	O

Antimicrobial	O
resistance	O
in	O
bacteria	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
less	O
severe	O
than	O
the	O
second	O
wave	O
but	O
still	O
much	O
more	O
deadly	O
than	O
the	O
initial	O
first	O
wave	O
.	O

The	O
report	O
identified	O
seven	O
experiments	O
of	O
concern	O
,	O
including	O
those	O
that	O
would	O
enhance	O
the	O
virulence	O
of	O
a	O
pathogen	O
and	O
demonstrate	O
how	O
to	O
render	O
a	O
vaccine	O
ineffective	O
.	O

Roger	B-Person
Wicker	E-Person
,	O
R-Mississippi	S-Organization
.	O
A	O
laboratory	O
in	O
Maryland	S-Location
confirmed	O
the	O
presence	O
of	O
ricin	S-Pathogen
after	O
initial	O
field	O
tests	O
indicated	O
the	O
poison	O
was	O
present	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
Senate	S-Organization
Sergeant-at-Arms	O
.	O

[Discussion	O
section	O
,	O
8th	O
paragraph]	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
half	O
of	O
CT	B-Technology
scans	E-Technology
are	O
contrast	B-Drug
CTs	E-Drug
using	O
intravenously	O
injected	O
radiocontrast	O
agents	O
.	O

Discussions	O
on	O
the	O
content	O
,	O
promulgation	O
,	O
and	O
adoption	O
of	O
codes	O
of	O
conduct	O
were	O
completed	O
in	O
December	O
2005	O
by	O
States	O
Party	O
to	O
the	O
Biological	B-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Weapons	I-International_exchange_and_cooperation
Convention	E-International_exchange_and_cooperation

In	O
its	O
statement	O
,	O
Vector	S-Organization
said	O
that	O
no	O
biohazard	O
material	O
was	O
being	O
stored	O
in	O
the	O
room	O
where	O
the	O
explosion	O
took	O
place	O
.	O

"	O
It	O
is	O
our	O
opinion	O
that	O
the	O
knowledge	O
to	O
be	O
gained	O
from	O
this	O
program	O
appears	O
very	O
limited	O
in	O
its	O
capacity	O
to	O
enhance	O
U.S.	O
agriculture	O
or	O
respond	O
to	O
national	O
emergencies,	O
"	O
the	O
authors	O
wrote	O
.	O

As	O
is	O
common	O
with	O
infections	O
,	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
delay	O
between	O
the	O
moment	O
a	O
person	O
is	O
first	O
infected	O
and	O
the	O
time	O
he	O
or	O
she	O
develops	O
symptoms	O
.	O

Agencies	O
involved	O
in	O
producing	O
policies	O
surrounding	O
biosafety	O
within	O
a	O
hospital	O
,	O
pharmacy	O
or	O
clinical	O
research	O
laboratory	O
include:	O
the	O
CDC	O
,	O
FDA	O
,	O
USDA	O
,	O
DHHS	O
,	O
DoT	S-Organization
and	O
potentially	O
other	O
local	O
organizations	O
including	O
public	O
health	O
departments	O
.	O

ResistanceMap	S-Platform
is	O
a	O
website	O
by	O
the	O
licy	O
and	O
provides	O
data	O
on	O
antimicrobial	O
resistance	O
on	O
a	O
global	O
level	O
.	O

A	O
jet	O
aircraft	O
released	O
material	O
over	O
Victoria	S-Location
Texas	S-Location
,	O
that	O
was	O
monitored	O
in	O
the	O
.	O

The	O
committee	O
will	O
also	O
discuss	O
vaccines	O
for	O
human	B-Pathogen
papillomavirus	E-Pathogen
,	O
Japanese	B-Pathogen
encephalitis	E-Pathogen
and	O
.	O

The	O
subject	O
was	O
not	O
pursued	O
further	O
by	O
Sutton	S-Person
,	O
who	O
was	O
probably	O
unaware	O
of	O
's	O
activities	O
.	O

Martin	S-Person
,	O
James	B-Person
W.	E-Person
,	O
George	B-Person
W.	I-Person
Christopher	E-Person
and	O
Edward	B-Person
M.	I-Person
Eitzen	E-Person
(2007)	O
,	O
"	O
History	O
of	O
Biological	O
Weapons:	O
From	O
Poisoned	O
Darts	O
to	O
Intentional	O
Epidemics"	O
,	O
In:	O
Dembek,	B-Person
Zygmunt	I-Person
F.	E-Person
(2007)	O
,	O
Medical	O
Aspects	O
of	O
Biological	O
Warfare	O
,	O
(Series:	O
Textbooks	O
of	O
Military	O
Medicine)	O
,	O
Washington,	B-Location
DC	E-Location
:	O
,	O
pg	O
11	O
.	O

Some	O
results	O
(such	O
as	O
the	O
study)	O
have	O
received	O
substantial	O
press	O
coverage	O
without	O
first	O
passing	O
through	O
peer	O
review	O
.	O

Both	O
of	O
those	O
are	O
part	O
of	O
Dorsey	S-Person
routine	O
,	O
which	O
he	O
detailed	O
in	O
a	O
podcast	O
interview	O
.	O

Restriction	O
enzymes	O
changed	O
genetics	O
because	O
they	O
allow	O
scientists	O
to	O
cut	O
and	O
paste	O
pieces	O
of	O
DNA	O
,	O
although	O
it	O
took	O
two	O
more	O
scientists	O
to	O
realize	O
their	O
potential	O
.	O

In	O
1970	O
and	O
1972	O
,	O
Sand	B-Scientific_research_project
Fly	I-Scientific_research_project
Fever	E-Scientific_research_project
tests	O
were	O
performed	O
on	O
humans	O
according	O
to	O
a	O
declassified	O
US	B-Organization
Army	E-Organization
report	O
–	O
US	B-Organization
Army	E-Organization
Activities	O
in	O
the	O
US	S-Location
,	O
Biological	O
Warfare	O
Programs	O
,	O
1977	O
,	O
vol.II	O
,	O
p.	O
203	O
During	O
operation	O
Whitecoat	O
volunteers	O
were	O
exposed	O
to	O
bites	O
by	O
infected	O
sand	O
flies	O
.	O

Health	O
officials	O
use	O
the	O
virus'	O
clinical	O
name	O
--	O
H1N1	S-Pathogen
--	O
to	O
reflect	O
that	O
it's	O
actually	O
a	O
combination	O
of	O
several	O
different	O
types	O
of	O
and	O
to	O
reduce	O
confusion	O
about	O
whether	O
eating	O
pork	O
can	O
spread	O
the	O
virus.It	O
cannot	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
Pacific	S-Location
American	O
Samoa	S-Location
and	O
the	O
French	O
colony	O
of	O
New	B-Location
Caledonia	E-Location
also	O
succeeded	O
in	O
preventing	O
even	O
a	O
single	O
death	O
from	O
influenza	S-Disease
through	O
effective	O
quarantines	O
.	O

Rather	O
than	O
closing	O
schools	O
,	O
the	O
CDC	S-Organization
recommended	O
that	O
students	O
and	O
school	O
workers	O
with	O
flu	O
symptoms	O
should	O
stay	O
home	O
for	O
either	O
seven	O
days	O
total	O
,	O
or	O
until	O
24	O
hours	O
after	O
symptoms	O
subsided	O
,	O
whichever	O
was	O
longer	O
.	O

By	O
the	O
end	O
of	O
the	O
program	O
,	O
seeks	O
to	O
demonstrate	O
in	O
controlled	O
laboratory	O
conditions	O
the	O
suppression	O
of	O
viral	O
jump	O
to	O
a	O
new	O
species	O
.	O

Immediately	O
following	O
the	O
incident	O
in	O
Frist's	O
office	O
,	O
both	O
the	O
FBI	S-Organization
and	O
the	O
United	B-Organization
States	I-Organization
Capitol	I-Organization
Police	E-Organization
were	O
tasked	O
to	O
the	O
investigation	O
;	O
like	O
in	O
the	O
Fallen	B-Activity
Angel	I-Activity
investigation	E-Activity
,	O
the	O
FBI	S-Organization
was	O
the	O
lead	O
agency	O
.	O

In	O
terms	O
of	O
the	O
,	O
you'd	O
have	O
to	O
direct	O
that	O
question	O
to	O
them	O
.	O

EK	S-Person
and	O
MC	S-Person
conceived	O
the	O
idea	O
for	O
this	O
project	O
.	O

One	O
study	O
estimated	O
that	O
as	O
many	O
as	O
0.	O
4%	O
of	O
current	O
cancers	O
in	O
the	O
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
are	O
due	O
to	O
CTs	S-Technology
performed	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
and	O
that	O
this	O
may	O
increase	O
to	O
as	O
high	O
as	O
1.	O
5	O
to	O
2%	O
with	O
2007	O
rates	O
of	O
CT	S-Technology
use	O
;	O
however	O
,	O
this	O
estimate	O
is	O
disputed	O
,	O
as	O
there	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
consensus	O
about	O
the	O
existence	O
of	O
damage	O
from	O
low	O
levels	O
of	O
radiation	O
.	O

The	O
isomers	O
were	O
then	O
separated	O
via	O
reversed-phase	B-Technology
HPLC	E-Technology
The	O
optically	O
pure	O
compound	O
and	O
intermediate	O
a	O
are	O
reacted	O
with	O
trimethyl	O
phosphate	O
and	O
methylimidazole	O
to	O
obtain	O
a	O
diastereomer	O
mixture	O
of	O
remdesivir	S-Drug
.	O
In	O
the	O
end	O
,	O
optically	O
pure	O
can	O
be	O
obtained	O
through	O
chiral	O
resolution	O
methods	O
.	O

So	O
when	O
something	O
like	O
this	O
happens	O
here	O
,	O
I'm	O
deeply	O
concerned	O
about	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
meeting	O
-	O
sponsored	O
by	O
the	O
Nuclear	B-Organization
Threat	I-Organization
Initiative	E-Organization
(	O
NTI	S-Organization
)	O
,	O
Oxford	B-Organization
University	E-Organization
,	O
and	O
-	O
included	O
representatives	O
from	O
13	O
countries	O
with	O
expertise	O
in	O
life	O
sciences	O
and	O
bioengineering	O
,	O
biodefense	O
and	O
biosecurity	O
,	O
science	O
policy	O
,	O
public	O
health	O
,	O
infectious	O
diseases	O
,	O
and	O
catastrophic	O
risks	O
.	O

People	O
in	O
at-risk	O
groups	O
should	O
be	O
treated	O
with	O
antivirals	O
(	O
oseltamivir	S-Drug
or	O
zanamivir	S-Drug
)	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
possible	O
when	O
they	O
first	O
experience	O
flu	O
symptoms	O
.	O

The	O
extremes	O
poles	O
are	O
simple	O
hyperlinks	O
connecting	O
resources	O
versus	O
full	O
integration	O
in	O
a	O
data	O
warehouse	O
structure	O
.	O

The	O
Black	B-Disease
Death	E-Disease
was	O
not	O
the	O
only	O
biological	O
disaster	O
to	O
scar	O
human	O
history	O
.	O

CDC	S-Organization
announced	O
today	O
that	O
approximately	O
75	O
Atlanta-based	O
staff	O
are	O
being	O
monitored	O
or	O
provided	O
antibiotics	S-Drug
because	O
they	O
may	O
have	O
been	O
unintentionally	O
exposed	O
to	O
live	O
Bacillus	B-Pathogen
anthracis	E-Pathogen
()	O
after	O
established	O
safety	O
practices	O
were	O
not	O
followed	O
.	O

Having	O
previously	O
gained	O
political	O
control	O
of	O
Antelope	S-Location
Oregon	S-Location
,	O
Rajneesh's	O
followers	O
,	O
who	O
were	O
based	O
in	O
nearby	O
Rajneeshpuram	S-Location
,	O
sought	O
election	O
to	O
two	O
of	O
the	O
three	O
seats	O
on	O
the	O
Wasco	B-Organization
County	I-Organization
Circuit	I-Organization
Court	E-Organization
that	O
were	O
up	O
for	O
election	O
in	O
November	O
1984	O
.	O

We	O
believe	O
that	O
collaboration	O
among	O
laboratories	O
will	O
be	O
central	O
when	O
it	O
comes	O
to	O
adapting	O
to	O
the	O
rapid	O
technical	O
development	O
that	O
is	O
now	O
ongoing	O
in	O
microbiology	O
laboratories	O
.	O

Ricin	S-Pathogen
,	O
a	O
substance	O
derived	O
from	O
castor	O
beans	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
used	O
in	O
bioterror	O
attacks	O
,	O
"	O
has	O
legitimate	O
lab	O
uses	O
in	O
very	O
small	O
quantities,	O
"	O
but	O
was	O
not	O
in	O
use	O
in	O
this	O
lab	O
,	O
the	O
memo	O
says	O
.	O

The	O
CFR	O
among	O
hospitalised	O
patients	O
,	O
based	O
on	O
the	O
three	O
intense-transmission	O
countries	O
,	O
was	O
between	O
57%	O
and	O
59%	O
in	O
January	O
2015	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
case	O
of	O
SARS-CoV-2	S-Pathogen
,	O
such	O
research	O
focuses	O
on	O
the	O
S-spike	O
protein	O
that	O
helps	O
the	O
virus	O
intrude	O
the	O
ACE2	O
enzyme	O
receptor	O
.	O

The	O
synthetic	B-Technology
genomics	I-Technology
research	E-Technology
at	O
JCVI	S-Organization
has	O
undergone	O
review	O
at	O
the	O
highest	O
levels	O
of	O
the	O
US	S-Location
government	O
.	O

Zilinskas	S-Person
,	O
Raymond	B-Person
A.	E-Person
(1999)	O
,	O
"	O
Iraq	S-Location
's	O
Biological	O
Warfare	O
Program:	O
The	O
Past	O
as	O
Future?	O
"	O
,	O
Chapter	O
8	O
in:	O
Lederberg	S-Person
,	O
Joshua	S-Person
(editor)	O
,	O
Biological	O
Weapons:	O
Limiting	O
the	O
Threat	O
(1999)	O
,	O
The	O
MIT	O
Press	O
,	O
pg	O
138	O
.	O

These	O
established	O
trends	O
can	O
then	O
be	O
observed	O
by	O
medical	O
epidemiologists	O
to	O
determine	O
if	O
there	O
are	O
any	O
disease	O
outbreaks	O
in	O
any	O
particular	O
locales	O
;	O
maps	O
of	O
disease	O
prevalence	O
can	O
then	O
be	O
created	O
rather	O
easily	O
.	O

In	O
Philadelphia	S-Location
for	O
example	O
,	O
4,597 people	O
died	O
in	O
the	O
week	O
ending	O
16 October	O
,	O
but	O
by	O
11 November	O
,	O
influenza	S-Disease
had	O
almost	O
disappeared	O
from	O
the	O
city	O
.	O

Because	O
of	O
the	O
Lead	B-Incident
contamination	I-Incident
in	I-Incident
Washington,	I-Incident
D.C.	I-Incident
drinking	I-Incident
water	E-Incident
the	O
United	B-Organization
States	I-Organization
House	I-Organization
of	I-Organization
Representatives	E-Organization
conducted	O
an	O
investigation	O
,	O
that	O
uncovered	O
that	O
the	O
CDC	S-Organization
had	O
made	O
claims	O
in	O
a	O
report	O
that	O
had	O
indicated	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
risk	O
from	O
high	O
lead	O
levels	O
-	O
although	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
opposite	O
.	O

The	O
new	O
provisions	O
allowed	O
drivers	O
to	O
stay	O
on	O
duty	O
for	O
only	O
14	O
hours	O
,	O
thus	O
the	O
time	O
spent	O
waiting	O
could	O
eat	O
into	O
the	O
time	O
a	O
driver	O
spent	O
on	O
duty	O
.	O

No	O
geographic	O
or	O
chronologic	O
indication	O
exists	O
to	O
suggest	O
that	O
one	O
of	O
these	O
variants	O
was	O
the	O
precursor	O
of	O
the	O
other	O
,	O
nor	O
are	O
there	O
consistent	O
differences	O
between	O
the	O
case	O
histories	O
or	O
histopathologic	O
features	O
of	O
the	O
5	O
patients	O
infected	O
with	O
them	O
.	O

He	O
found	O
archival	O
evidence	O
that	O
a	O
respiratory	O
illness	O
that	O
struck	O
northern	O
China	S-Location
in	O
November	O
1917	O
was	O
identified	O
a	O
year	O
later	O
by	O
Chinese	O
health	O
officials	O
as	O
identical	O
to	O
the	O
.	O

To	O
create	O
a	O
T1-weighted	O
image	O
,	O
magnetization	O
is	O
allowed	O
to	O
recover	O
before	O
measuring	O
the	O
MR	O
signal	O
by	O
changing	O
the	O
repetition	O
time	O
(TR)	O
.	O

This	O
past	O
May	O
,	O
legislation	O
that	O
would	O
create	O
a	O
national	O
defense	O
strategy	O
was	O
introduced	O
in	O
the	O
Senate	S-Organization
,	O
coinciding	O
with	O
the	O
timing	O
of	O
ISIS-affiliated	O
terrorist	O
groups	O
get	O
closer	O
to	O
weaponizing	O
biological	O
agents	O
.	O

KATHERINE	B-Person
LYON	I-Person
DANIEL	E-Person
Good	O
morning	O
.	O

This	O
problem	O
stems	O
from	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
the	O
population	O
difference	O
between	O
the	O
nuclear	O
spin	O
states	O
is	O
very	O
small	O
at	O
room	O
temperature	O
.	O

The	O
Marburg	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
is	O
in	O
the	O
same	O
family	O
as	O
Ebola	S-Pathogen
and	O
causes	O
severe	O
hemorrhagic	B-Disease
fever	E-Disease
in	O
humans	O
.	O

In	O
January	O
2020	O
,	O
the	O
World	B-Organization
Health	I-Organization
Organisation	E-Organization
recommended	O
2019-nCov	S-Disease
and	O
2019-nCoV	B-Disease
acute	I-Disease
respiratory	I-Disease
disease	E-Disease
as	O
interim	O
names	O
for	O
the	O
virus	O
and	O
disease	O
per	O
2015	O
guidance	O
and	O
international	O
guidelines	O
against	O
using	O
geographical	O
locations	O
(e.g	O
.	O

An	O
estimated	O
date	O
for	O
its	O
appearance	O
in	O
mammalian	O
hosts	O
has	O
been	O
put	O
at	O
the	O
period	O
1882–1913	O
.	O

Jacob	S-Person
told	O
us	O
.	O

"	O
It's	O
our	O
honor	O
and	O
duty	O
to	O
support	O
our	O
military	O
personnel	O
by	O
ensuring	O
they	O
have	O
access	O
to	O
safe	O
and	O
effective	O
medical	O
products	O
–	O
especially	O
products	O
that	O
meet	O
the	O
unique	O
needs	O
and	O
settings	O
in	O
which	O
soldiers	O
may	O
require	O
medical	O
treatment,	O
"	O
said	O
FDA	S-Organization
Commissioner	O
.	O

Higher	O
resolution	O
is	O
not	O
always	O
suitable	O
for	O
any	O
given	O
scenario	O
,	O
such	O
as	O
detection	O
of	O
small	O
.	O

Greg	B-Person
Bear	E-Person
makes	O
reference	O
to	O
the	O
Sverdlovsk	B-Incident
anthrax	I-Incident
leak	E-Incident
in	O
Quantico	S-Document
,	O
a	O
novel	O
about	O
genetically	O
engineered	O
pathogens	O
and	O
agents	O
trying	O
to	O
stop	O
their	O
release	O
.	O

The	O
company	O
has	O
been	O
awarded	O
a	O
$344.	O
4	O
million	O
federal	O
contract	O
(2006	O
–	O
2016)	O
and	O
another	O
$17.	O
3	O
million	O
contract	O
(2015	O
-2026)	O
by	O
.	O

All	O
manipulations	O
of	O
potentially	O
infectious	O
diagnostic	O
materials	O
,	O
isolates	O
,	O
and	O
naturally	O
or	O
experimentally	O
infected	O
animals	O
pose	O
a	O
high	O
risk	O
of	O
exposure	O
and	O
infection	O
to	O
laboratory	O
personnel	O
,	O
the	O
community	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
environment	O
.	O

Definitive	O
confirmation	O
of	O
the	O
role	O
of	O
Y.	B-Pathogen
pestis	E-Pathogen
arrived	O
in	O
2010	O
with	O
a	O
publication	O
in	O
PLOS	B-Organization
Pathogens	I-Organization
by	I-Organization
Haensch	E-Organization
et	O
al	O
.	O

The	O
package	O
also	O
includes	O
a	O
salaries	O
tax	O
rebate	O
and	O
reduced	O
rates	O
.	O

Orthogonal	B-Technology
CRISPR	I-Technology
experiments	E-Technology
are	O
often	O
recommended	O
to	O
confirm	O
the	O
results	O
of	O
a	O
experiment	O
.	O

The	O
would	O
be	O
scalable	O
to	O
cover	O
a	O
major	O
metropolitan	O
city	O
and	O
its	O
surrounding	O
region	O
.	O

As	O
of	O
this	O
printing	O
,	O
there	O
are	O
no	O
experiments	O
described	O
in	O
this	O
manual	O
,	O
which	O
specifically	O
utilize	O
BSL‐4	S-Platform
containment	O
.	O

This	O
putative	O
treatment	O
sounds	O
vampiric	O
,	O
yet	O
it's	O
gained	O
popularity	O
in	O
the	O
Silicon	B-Location
Valley	E-Location
area	O
,	O
where	O
people	O
have	O
actually	O
paid	O
$8,000	O
a	O
pop	O
to	O
participate	O
in	O
trials	O
.	O

We	O
will	O
continue	O
to	O
innovate	O
.	O

These	O
drugs	O
prevent	O
viruses	O
from	O
reproducing	O
by	O
inhibiting	O
essential	O
stages	O
of	O
the	O
virus's	O
replication	O
cycle	O
in	O
infected	O
cells	O
.	O

As	O
I	O
said	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
determined	O
to	O
get	O
to	O
zero	O
cases	O
,	O
and	O
long	O
after	O
this	O
epidemic	O
is	O
over	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
need	O
that	O
resolve	O
to	O
meet	O
new	O
challenges	O
wherever	O
and	O
however	O
they	O
arise	O
.	O

These	O
events	O
should	O
never	O
happen	O
.	O

One	O
of	O
the	O
two	O
,	O
a	O
physician	O
,	O
had	O
worked	O
with	O
patients	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
other	O
was	O
assisting	O
workers	O
to	O
get	O
in	O
and	O
out	O
of	O
their	O
protective	B-Equipment
gear	E-Equipment
while	O
wearing	O
herself	O
.	O

As	O
primates	O
in	O
the	O
area	O
were	O
not	O
found	O
to	O
be	O
infected	O
and	O
fruit	O
bats	O
do	O
not	O
live	O
near	O
the	O
location	O
of	O
the	O
initial	O
zoonotic	O
transmission	O
event	O
in	O
Meliandou	S-Location
,	O
it	O
is	O
suspected	O
that	O
the	O
index	O
case	O
occurred	O
after	O
a	O
child	O
had	O
contact	O
with	O
an	O
insectivorous	O
bat	O
from	O
a	O
colony	O
of	O
Angolan	O
free-tailed	O
bats	O
near	O
the	O
village	O
.	O

The	O
noticeable	O
general	O
trend	O
was	O
the	O
international	O
donor	O
interest	O
in	O
the	O
BMENA	S-Location
region	O
in	O
2001–2013	O
.	O

As	O
was	O
true	O
for	O
the	O
,	O
the	O
second	O
1891	O
recurrence	O
produced	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
deaths	O
.	O

For	O
example	O
,	O
Palestine	S-Organization
attends	O
meetings	O
of	O
the	O
.	O
Each	O
region	O
also	O
has	O
a	O
regional	O
office	O
.	O

This	O
isolate	O
belonged	O
to	O
sequence	O
type	O
167	O
(ST167)	O
.	O

Although	O
it	O
was	O
a	O
major	O
scientific	O
success	O
,	O
the	O
project	O
raised	O
lots	O
of	O
questions	O
about	O
how	O
synthetic	O
genomes	O
could	O
be	O
used	O
,	O
for	O
good	O
or	O
bad	O
,	O
and	O
what	O
the	O
political	O
and	O
societal	O
implications	O
were	O
.	O

This	O
council	O
could	O
help	O
identify	O
redundancies	O
and	O
gaps	O
in	O
our	O
biodefense	O
before	O
they	O
wind	O
up	O
costing	O
lives	O
and	O
wasting	O
dollars	O
.	O

It	O
caused	O
significant	O
mortality	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
case	O
fatality	O
rate	O
reported	O
which	O
was	O
initially	O
considerable	O
,	O
while	O
the	O
rate	O
among	O
hospitalised	O
patients	O
was	O
57–59%	O
,	O
the	O
final	O
numbers	O
28,616	O
people	O
,	O
including	O
11,310	O
deaths	O
,	O
for	O
a	O
case-fatality	O
rate	O
of	O
40%	O
.	O

The	O
disease	O
was	O
declared	O
eradicated	O
from	O
human	O
populations	O
in	O
1980	O
.	O

At	O
least	O
29	O
phase	B-Activity
II–IV	I-Activity
efficacy	I-Activity
trials	I-Activity
in	I-Activity
COVID‑19	E-Activity
were	O
concluded	O
in	O
March	O
2020	O
,	O
or	O
scheduled	O
to	O
provide	O
results	O
in	O
April	O
from	O
hospitals	O
in	O
.	O
There	O
are	O
more	O
than	O
300	O
active	O
clinical	O
trials	O
underway	O
as	O
of	O
April	O
2020	O
.	O

"	O
Our	O
aim	O
is	O
to	O
develop	O
rapid	O
and	O
reliable	O
diagnostic	O
methods	O
,	O
as	O
well	O
as	O
to	O
find	O
ways	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
risk	O
of	O
melioidosis	S-Pathogen
in	O
deployed	O
service	O
members,	O
"	O
said	O
.	O

These	O
proteins	O
protect	O
the	O
bacterial	O
cell	O
from	O
antibiotics	O
that	O
target	O
the	O
cell's	O
ribosomes	O
to	O
inhibit	O
protein	O
synthesis	O
.	O

Every	O
user	O
can	O
also	O
check	O
the	O
status	O
of	O
three	O
other	O
users	O
.	O

On	O
21	O
September	O
,	O
officials	O
of	O
the	O
DRC	S-Location
indicated	O
a	O
confirmed	O
case	O
of	O
EVD	S-Disease
at	O
Lake	B-Location
Albert	E-Location
,	O
an	O
entry	O
point	O
into	O
,	O
though	O
no	O
cases	O
were	O
then	O
confirmed	O
within	O
Ugandan	O
territory	O
.	O

The	O
Agenda	O
was	O
launched	O
on	O
a	O
bitterly	O
cold	O
and	O
snowy	O
day	O
,	O
when	O
roads	O
and	O
offices	O
across	O
Washington	S-Location
were	O
closed	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
instead	O
ordered	O
that	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
1-2	O
aerial	O
sprayings	O
of	O
the	O
infected	O
communities	O
,	O
more	O
than	O
a	O
dozen	O
sprayings	O
would	O
be	O
necessary	O
over	O
a	O
period	O
of	O
months	O
.	O

Although	O
PREEMPT	S-Scientific_research_project
is	O
a	O
fundamental	O
research	O
program	O
,	O
is	O
aware	O
of	O
biosafety	O
and	O
biosecurity	O
sensitivities	O
that	O
could	O
arise	O
.	O

As	O
of	O
May	O
2020	O
this	O
pandemic	O
had	O
nearly	O
4	O
million	O
confirmed	O
cases	O
worldwide	O
,	O
and	O
over	O
270,000	O
associated	O
deaths	O
.	O

In	O
2000	O
,	O
the	O
FDA	S-Organization
announced	O
their	O
intention	O
to	O
revoke	O
approval	O
of	O
fluoroquinolone	O
use	O
in	O
poultry	O
production	O
because	O
of	O
substantial	O
evidence	O
linking	O
it	O
to	O
the	O
emergence	O
of	O
fluoroquinolone-resistant	B-Disease
Campylobacter	I-Disease
infections	E-Disease
in	O
humans	O
.	O

News	O
of	O
the	O
infection	O
will	O
stoke	O
concerns	O
about	O
its	O
spread	O
in	O
a	O
country	O
which	O
is	O
by	O
far	O
the	O
world's	O
largest	O
producer	O
of	O
pork	O
.	O

Most	O
infections	O
with	O
human	O
coronaviruses	O
are	O
mild	O
and	O
associated	O
with	O
common	B-Disease
colds	E-Disease
The	O
seven	O
coronaviruses	O
known	O
to	O
infect	O
humans	O
are	O
in	O
the	O
alpha	O
and	O
beta	O
genera	O
.	O

There	O
is	O
no	O
spinning	O
here,	O
"	O
and	O
further	O
stating	O
that	O
"	O
I	O
know	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
pressure	O
on	O
WHO	S-Organization
when	O
we	O
appreciate	O
what	O
is	O
doing	O
but	O
because	O
of	O
pressure	O
we	O
should	O
not	O
fail	O
to	O
tell	O
the	O
truth	O
,	O
we	O
don't	O
say	O
anything	O
to	O
appease	O
anyone	O
.	O

Source:	O
Naval	B-Organization
Medical	I-Organization
Research	I-Organization
Center	E-Organization
edited	O
.	O

Attending	O
experts	O
use	O
the	O
occasion	O
to	O
address	O
the	O
emergence	O
,	O
spread	O
and	O
control	O
of	O
these	O
diseases	O
,	O
covering	O
a	O
host	O
of	O
health	O
threats	O
that	O
affect	O
both	O
and	O
its	O
colleagues	O
in	O
the	O
international	O
scene	O
.	O

The	O
-	O
the	O
flu	B-Pathogen
strain	E-Pathogen
that	O
your	O
lab	O
thought	O
it	O
was	O
sending	O
isn't	O
identified	O
,	O
but	O
it	O
was	O
going	O
to	O
a	O
bsl-3	S-Platform
lab	O
.	O

The	O
genetically	B-Pathogen
engineered	I-Pathogen
'superbug'	E-Pathogen
lethal	O
and	O
resistant	O
to	O
environmental	O
influence	O
or	O
any	O
medical	O
treatment-is	O
only	O
a	O
small	O
part	O
of	O
this	O
story	O
.	O

Its	O
guide	O
RNA	O
targets	O
regulatory	O
DNA	O
sequences	O
called	O
promoters	O
that	O
immediately	O
precede	O
the	O
target	O
gene	O
.	O

Based	O
on	O
these	O
findings	O
,	O
SIGA	S-Organization
is	O
continuing	O
to	O
move	O
tecovirimat	S-Drug
forward	O
as	O
a	O
treatment	O
for	O
smallpox	S-Pathogen
.	O
"	O
Smallpox	S-Pathogen
is	O
both	O
highly	O
contagious	O
and	O
highly	O
lethal	O
and	O
there	O
is	O
growing	O
concern	O
that	O
smallpox	S-Pathogen
could	O
be	O
used	O
as	O
a	O
potential	O
bioweapon,	O
"	O
said	O
Phil	B-Person
Gomez	E-Person
,	O
PhD	O
,	O
SIGA	S-Organization
's	O
Chief	O
Executive	O
Officer	O
in	O
a	O
statement	O
from	O
the	O
company.	O
"	O
A	O
bioterror	O
attack	O
could	O
be	O
especially	O
damaging	O
because	O
the	O
majority	O
of	O
today's	O
population	O
is	O
not	O
immune	O
to	O
the	O
virus	O
,	O
as	O
routine	O
vaccination	O
ended	O
in	O
the	O
1970s	O
.	O

The	O
biological	O
and	O
chemical	O
weapons	O
developed	O
during	O
that	O
period	O
were	O
tested	O
at	O
the	O
Dugway	B-Location
Proving	I-Location
Grounds	I-Location
in	I-Location
Utah	E-Location
.	O
Soon	O
there	O
were	O
facilities	O
for	O
the	O
mass	O
production	O
of	O
anthrax	B-Pathogen
spores	E-Pathogen
,	O
brucellosis	S-Pathogen
,	O
and	O
,	O
although	O
the	O
war	O
was	O
over	O
before	O
these	O
weapons	O
could	O
be	O
of	O
much	O
operational	O
use	O
.	O

When	O
Edward	B-Person
Jenner	E-Person
invented	O
vaccines	O
and	O
when	O
Alexander	B-Person
Fleming	E-Person
discovered	O
,	O
they	O
were	O
harnessing	O
the	O
power	O
of	O
biotechnology	O
.	O

The	O
flu	O
that	O
winter	O
was	O
beyond	O
imagination	O
as	O
millions	O
were	O
infected	O
and	O
thousands	O
died	O
.	O

In	O
a	O
summary	O
by	O
the	O
GAO	S-Organization
the	O
Secretary	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
the	I-Organization
Army	E-Organization
has	O
gone	O
so	O
far	O
as	O
to	O
implement	O
a	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
organization	O
has	O
not	O
created	O
the	O
strategy	O
and	O
execution	O
for	O
managing	O
the	O
initiative	O
.	O

The	O
effectiveness	O
of	O
potential	O
treatments	O
for	O
any	O
disease	O
is	O
usually	O
assessed	O
in	O
a	O
randomised	O
controlled	O
trial	O
,	O
which	O
compares	O
the	O
outcome	O
of	O
those	O
who	O
received	O
treatment	O
to	O
those	O
who	O
received	O
a	O
placebo	O
(i.e.	O
dummy	O
treatment)	O
.	O

In	O
1949	O
,	O
Sulkin	S-Person
and	O
Pike	S-Person
published	O
the	O
first	O
serious	O
surveys	O
of	O
laboratory	O
associated	O
infections	O
.	O

All	O
personnel	O
authorized	O
to	O
enter	O
the	O
laboratory	O
must	O
be	O
well	O
trained	O
.	O

Basing	O
their	O
choice	O
on	O
"	O
the	O
person	O
or	O
persons	O
who	O
most	O
affected	O
the	O
news	O
and	O
our	O
lives	O
,	O
for	O
good	O
or	O
ill	O
,	O
and	O
embodied	O
what	O
was	O
important	O
about	O
the	O
year"	O
,	O
the	O
editors	O
of	O
Time	B-Organization
magazine	E-Organization
in	O
December	O
2014	O
named	O
the	O
Ebola	S-Disease
health	O
workers	O
as	O
Person	O
of	O
the	O
Year	O
.	O

Nevertheless	O
,	O
studies	O
suggest	O
that	O
many	O
people	O
are	O
still	O
able	O
to	O
purchase	O
these	O
drugs	O
without	O
official	O
recommendations	O
from	O
their	O
doctors	O
.	O

Y.	B-Pathogen
pestis	E-Pathogen
was	O
discovered	O
by	O
Alexandre	B-Person
Yersin	E-Person
,	O
a	O
pupil	O
of	O
Louis	B-Person
Pasteur	E-Person
,	O
during	O
an	O
epidemic	B-Incident
of	I-Incident
bubonic	I-Incident
plague	I-Incident
in	I-Incident
Hong	I-Incident
Kong	I-Incident
in	I-Incident
1894	E-Incident
;	O
Yersin	S-Person
also	O
proved	O
this	O
bacillus	S-Pathogen
was	O
present	O
in	O
rodents	O
and	O
suggested	O
the	O
rat	O
was	O
the	O
main	O
vehicle	O
of	O
transmission	O
.	O

Biotechnology	O
can	O
range	O
from	O
using	O
bacterial	O
strains	O
for	O
brewing	O
beer	O
to	O
editing	O
genes	O
using	O
CRISPR	S-Technology

Among	O
other	O
things	O
,	O
this	O
investigation	O
recommended	O
that	O
the	O
capacity	O
of	O
and	O
coordination	O
between	O
the	O
various	O
microbiology	O
laboratories	O
should	O
be	O
strengthened	O
,	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
ensure	O
a	O
diagnostic	O
service	O
that	O
is	O
sustainable	O
and	O
effective	O
in	O
the	O
event	O
of	O
any	O
crisis	O
generating	O
a	O
large	O
sample	O
load	O
.	O

Because	O
pigs	O
are	O
more	O
readily	O
infected	O
with	O
avian	O
viruses	O
than	O
are	O
humans	O
,	O
they	O
were	O
suggested	O
as	O
the	O
original	O
recipients	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
,	O
passing	O
the	O
virus	O
to	O
humans	O
sometime	O
between	O
1913	O
and	O
1918	O
.	O

We've	O
already	O
begun	O
the	O
process	O
of	O
analyzing	O
the	O
entire	O
genetic	O
sequence	O
of	O
the	O
smallpox	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
,	O
and	O
we'll	O
see	O
whether	O
any	O
of	O
the	O
remaining	O
four	O
vials	O
grow	O
.	O

CDC	S-Organization
also	O
reported	O
findings	O
of	O
an	O
internal	B-Document
CDC	I-Document
investigation	E-Document
on	O
the	O
H5N1	B-Incident
flu	I-Incident
lab	I-Incident
incident	E-Incident
,	O
and	O
actions	O
taken	O
in	O
response	O
to	O
findings	O
of	O
both	O
the	O
APHIS	S-Organization
and	O
CDC	S-Organization
investigations	O
into	O
the	O
.	O

The	O
Breeders	O
claimed	O
that	O
it	O
was	O
responsible	O
for	O
the	O
summer	O
release	O
of	O
the	O
medflies	O
as	O
retaliation	O
for	O
the	O
environmental	O
damage	O
caused	O
by	O
the	O
Malathion	O
aerial	O
spraying	O
by	O
the	O
state	O
.	O

He	O
reported	O
that	O
in	O
thirteen	O
studies	O
of	O
hospitalized	O
women	O
in	O
the	O
pandemic	O
,	O
the	O
death	O
rate	O
ranged	O
from	O
23%	O
to	O
71%	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
there	O
have	O
been	O
credible	O
concerns	O
that	O
some	O
countries	O
used	O
it	O
to	O
create	O
bioweapons	O
.	O

In	O
principle	O
,	O
rather	O
than	O
transporting	O
samples	O
to	O
a	O
different	O
laboratory	O
in	O
the	O
network	O
,	O
an	O
alternative	O
would	O
be	O
to	O
exchange	O
staff	O
,	O
as	O
the	O
network	O
members'	O
staff	O
are	O
now	O
familiar	O
with	O
the	O
methods	O
and	O
practices	O
used	O
in	O
the	O
other	O
laboratories	O
.	O

MRI	S-Technology
was	O
originally	O
called	O
NMRI	S-Technology
(	O
nuclear	B-Technology
magnetic	I-Technology
resonance	I-Technology
imaging	E-Technology
)	O
,	O
but	O
"	O
nuclear"	O
was	O
dropped	O
to	O
avoid	O
negative	O
associations	O
.	O

To	O
avoid	O
blundering	O
into	O
disaster	O
,	O
the	O
errors	O
of	O
the	O
past	O
should	O
be	O
acknowledged	O
.	O

We	O
are	O
anticipating	O
a	O
scenario	O
of	O
continued	O
intense	O
transmission"	O
.	O

Construction	O
work	O
lagged	O
behind	O
schedule	O
and	O
costs	O
are	O
higher	O
than	O
originally	O
estimated	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
Dr	O
.	O

The	O
Homeland	B-Organization
Security	I-Organization
Department	E-Organization
wants	O
a	O
way	O
to	O
tap	O
into	O
nationwide	O
medical	O
databases	O
to	O
help	O
detect	O
and	O
respond	O
to	O
"	O
nationally	O
significant	O
"	O
biological	O
events	O
.	O

MERS	B-Disease
coronavirus	E-Disease
.	O
Ebola	S-Disease
.	O
Hepatitis	B-Disease
E	E-Disease
.	O
Yellow	B-Disease
Fever	E-Disease
.	O
Lassa	S-Disease
.	O
.	O

Pathogenic	O
micro-organisms	O
,	O
although	O
they	O
represent	O
only	O
a	O
small	O
part	O
in	O
the	O
total	O
microbial	O
world	O
,	O
receive	O
much	O
attention	O
because	O
they	O
represent	O
a	O
threat	O
for	O
the	O
human	O
or	O
animal	O
health	O
,	O
or	O
for	O
the	O
agriculture	O
.	O

Tafari	B-Person
Makonnen	E-Person
(the	O
future	O
Haile	B-Person
Selassie	E-Person
,	O
Emperor	O
of	O
Ethiopia	S-Location
)	O
was	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
first	O
Ethiopians	O
who	O
contracted	O
influenza	S-Disease
but	O
survived	O
.	O

Movies	O
have	O
been	O
made	O
about	O
this	O
place	O
saving	O
the	O
world	O
.	O

As	O
they	O
fled	O
the	O
besieged	O
cities	O
these	O
civilians	O
,	O
the	O
British	O
hoped	O
,	O
would	O
carry	O
to	O
rebel	O
troops	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
U.S.	S-Location
about	O
28%	O
of	O
the	O
population	O
of	O
105	O
million	O
became	O
infected	O
,	O
and	O
500,000	O
to	O
850,000	O
died	O
(0.48	O
to	O
0.81	O
percent	O
of	O
the	O
population	O
)	O
.	O
influenza	S-Disease
-and-	O
pneumonia	S-Disease
-pandemic-nationwide-820000-850000/The	O
Great	O
Pandemic:	O
The	O
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
in	O
1918–1919	O
,	O
U.S.	B-Organization
Department	I-Organization
of	I-Organization
Health	I-Organization
&amp;	I-Organization
Human	I-Organization
Serv	E-Organization
ices	O
.	O

In	O
his	O
speech	O
Nixon	O
called	O
his	O
move	O
"	O
unprecedented";	O
and	O
it	O
was	O
in	O
fact	O
the	O
first	O
review	O
of	O
the	O
U.S.	O
biological	O
warfare	O
program	O
since	O
1954	O
.	O

As	O
people	O
celebrated	O
Armistice	O
Day	O
with	O
parades	O
and	O
large	O
partiess	O
,	O
a	O
complete	O
disaster	O
from	O
the	O
public	O
health	O
standpoint	O
,	O
a	O
rebirth	O
of	O
the	O
epidemic	O
occurred	O
in	O
some	O
cities	O
.	O

Their	O
efforts	O
included	O
installing	O
hand-washing	O
stations	O
and	O
distributing	O
millions	O
of	O
bars	O
of	O
soap	O
and	O
chlorine	O
and	O
plans	O
for	O
taking	O
the	O
temperature	O
of	O
children	O
and	O
staff	O
at	O
the	O
school	O
gate	O
.	O

Reports	O
say	O
they	O
have	O
made	O
anthrax	S-Pathogen
more	O
deadly	O
still	O
through	O
genetic	O
engineering	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
a	O
United	O
States	O
federal	O
agency	O
,	O
under	O
the	O
Department	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Health	I-Organization
and	I-Organization
Human	I-Organization
Services	E-Organization
and	O
is	O
headquartered	O
in	O
Atlanta	O
,	O
.	O

Belgium	S-Organization
recalled	O
100,000	O
unusable	O
masks	O
,	O
which	O
were	O
thought	O
to	O
be	O
from	O
China	S-Location
but	O
were	O
in	O
fact	O
from	O
Colombia	S-Location
.	O
The	O
Philippines	S-Organization
stopped	O
using	O
test	O
kits	O
donated	O
by	O
China	S-Location
due	O
to	O
their	O
40	O
percent	O
accuracy	O
.	O

The	O
MoU	S-Document
authorizes	O
the	O
FDA	S-Organization
and	O
the	O
Pentagon	S-Organization
to	O
work	O
toward	O
faster	O
deployment	O
of	O
medical	O
products	O
meant	O
to	O
diagnose	O
,	O
treat	O
or	O
prevent	O
life-threatening	O
conditions	O
affecting	O
service	O
members	O
,	O
including	O
those	O
caused	O
by	O
chemical	O
,	O
biological	O
,	O
radiological	O
or	O
nuclear	O
agents	O
.	O

Speaking	O
during	O
the	O
occasion	O
,	O
USA	S-Organization
Ambassador	O
to	O
Cameroon	S-Organization
,	O
Peter	B-Person
Henry	I-Person
Barlerin	E-Person
said	O
the	O
Centre	O
equipped	O
with	O
the	O
state-of-the	O
art	O
equipment	O
including	O
computers	O
,	O
was	O
constructed	O
by	O
the	O
USAbased	O
company	O
.	O

The	O
FDA	S-Organization
Fast	O
Track	O
designation	O
is	O
a	O
process	O
designed	O
to	O
facilitate	O
the	O
development	O
and	O
expedite	O
the	O
review	O
of	O
drugs	O
and	O
vaccines	O
for	O
serious	O
conditions	O
and	O
that	O
fill	O
an	O
unmet	O
medical	O
need	O
.	O

The	O
ring	O
trials	O
include	O
both	O
live	O
and	O
inactivated	O
samples	O
that	O
are	O
prepared	O
by	O
one	O
arranging	O
laboratory	O
and	O
sent	O
to	O
the	O
other	O
participating	O
agencies	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
also	O
a	O
variety	O
of	O
signal	O
amplification	O
schemes	O
based	O
on	O
chemical	O
exchange	O
that	O
increase	O
sensitivity	O
.	O

To	O
put	O
in	O
perspective	O
what	O
it	O
would	O
cost	O
today	O
to	O
fight	O
a	O
1918-like	O
influenza	B-Incident
pandemic	E-Incident
which	O
100	O
years	O
ago	O
killed	O
50	O
million	O
people	O
,	O
estimated	O
the	O
price	O
tag	O
at	O
$6	O
trillion	O
.	O

Now	O
DOIs	O
have	O
been	O
used	O
for	O
giving	O
credit	O
to	O
data	O
producers	O
,	O
e.g.	O
.	O

TOM	B-Person
FRIEDEN	E-Person
Well	O
,	O
first	O
off	O
,	O
to	O
clarify	O
a	O
few	O
things	O
,	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
delay	O
in	O
the	O
anthrax	B-Incident
exposure	I-Incident
incident	E-Incident
when	O
that	O
was	O
-	O
came	O
to	O
light	O
,	O
the	O
same	O
day	O
I	O
was	O
notified	O
,	O
and	O
we	O
began	O
our	O
response	O
.	O

Myself	O
,	O
adapting	O
the	O
current	O
CRISPR/Cas9	B-Technology
technology	E-Technology
to	O
my	O
research	O
project	O
,	O
I	O
came	O
up	O
with	O
.	O

Representative	O
results	O
are	O
shown	O
in	O
Fig.1	O
.	O

However	O
,	O
emergency	O
supplemental	O
funding	O
has	O
been	O
depleted	O
,	O
he	O
added	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
H7N9	B-Pathogen
influenza	I-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
is	O
currently	O
circulating	O
in	O
China	S-Location
.	O
"	O
We	O
are	O
concerned	O
with	O
the	O
ominous	O
trends	O
that	O
we	O
are	O
seeing,	O
"	O
said	O
.	O

The	O
effects	O
of	O
different	O
water	O
temperatures	O
were	O
tested	O
by	O
bludgeoning	O
the	O
victim	O
to	O
determine	O
if	O
any	O
areas	O
were	O
still	O
frozen	O
.	O

The	O
Roadmap	O
assumes	O
that	O
a	O
rapid	O
escalation	O
of	O
the	O
complementary	O
strategies	O
in	O
intense	O
transmission	O
,	O
resource-constrained	O
areas	O
will	O
allow	O
the	O
comprehensive	O
application	O
of	O
more	O
standard	O
containment	O
strategies	O
within	O
three	O
months.	O
"	O
The	O
report	O
included	O
an	O
assumption	O
that	O
some	O
country	O
or	O
countries	O
would	O
pay	O
the	O
required	O
cost	O
of	O
their	O
plan	O
,	O
estimated	O
at	O
half	O
a	O
billion	O
US	O
dollars	O
.	O

It	O
was	O
revealed	O
around	O
this	O
time	O
that	O
the	O
accident	O
was	O
caused	O
by	O
the	O
non-replacement	O
of	O
a	O
filter	S-Equipment
on	O
an	O
exhaust	O
at	O
the	O
facility	O
,	O
and	O
though	O
the	O
problem	O
was	O
quickly	O
rectified	O
,	O
it	O
was	O
too	O
late	O
to	O
prevent	O
a	O
release	O
.	O

The	O
new	O
and	O
upcoming	O
GM	S-Technology
crops	O
carrying	O
multiple	O
stacked	O
traits	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
commercialized	O
soon	O
warrant	O
sensitive	O
detection	O
methods	O
both	O
at	O
the	O
DNA	O
and	O
protein	O
levels	O
.	O

The	O
current	O
Director-General	O
is	O
Tedros	B-Person
Adhanom	E-Person
,	O
former	O
Health	O
Minister	O
and	O
Foreign	O
Minister	O
of	O
,	O
who	O
began	O
his	O
five-year	O
term	O
on	O
1	O
July	O
2017	O
.	O

12	O
.	O

Had	O
the	O
winds	O
been	O
blowing	O
in	O
the	O
direction	O
of	O
the	O
city	O
at	O
that	O
time	O
,	O
it	O
could	O
have	O
resulted	O
in	O
the	O
pathogen	O
being	O
spread	O
to	O
hundreds	O
of	O
thousands	O
of	O
people	O
.	O

But	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
large	O
amount	O
of	O
pesticides	O
used	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
also	O
estimated	O
that	O
less	O
than	O
0.	O
1%	O
of	O
those	O
antimicrobial	O
agents	O
,	O
actually	O
reach	O
their	O
targets	O
.	O

In	O
March	O
,	O
developed	O
a	O
tablet	O
that	O
could	O
be	O
cleaned	O
with	O
chlorine	O
;	O
it	O
is	O
charged	O
wirelessly	O
and	O
can	O
transmit	O
information	O
to	O
servers	O
outside	O
the	O
working	O
area	O
.	O

When	O
the	O
official	O
memo	O
is	O
released	O
,	O
or	O
if	O
we	O
or	O
AAU	S-Organization
receive	O
any	O
additional	O
information	O
,	O
we	O
will	O
keep	O
the	O
membership	O
informed	O
.	O

This	O
includes	O
at	O
least	O
five	O
viruses	O
that	O
are	O
considered	O
to	O
be	O
potential	O
biowarfare	O
agents	O
,	O
among	O
them	O
Ebola	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
Marburg	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
and	O
Venezuelan	B-Pathogen
equine	I-Pathogen
encephalitis	I-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
.	O
The	O
first	O
two	O
in	O
particular	O
are	O
very	O
rare	O
viruses	O
that	O
might	O
be	O
difficult	O
to	O
acquire	O
by	O
potential	O
bioweaponeers-according	O
to	O
rumours	O
,	O
members	O
of	O
the	O
Japanese	B-Organization
cult	I-Organization
Aum	I-Organization
Shinrikyo	E-Organization
,	O
famous	O
for	O
the	O
nerve	B-Incident
gas	I-Incident
attack	I-Incident
on	I-Incident
the	I-Incident
Tokyo	I-Incident
subway	E-Incident
,	O
tried	O
unsuccessfully	O
to	O
get	O
their	O
hands	O
on	O
Ebola	B-Pathogen
virus	E-Pathogen
during	O
an	B-Incident
outbreak	I-Incident
in	I-Incident
former	I-Incident
Zaire	I-Incident
in	I-Incident
the	I-Incident
1990s	E-Incident
.	O
Using	O
the	O
method	O
that	O
has	O
been	O
published	O
for	O
polio	S-Disease
,	O
such	O
a	O
group	O
or	O
an	O
interested	O
state	O
could	O
theoretically	O
construct	O
in	O
the	O
laboratory	O
.	O

See:	O
J.	B-Person
F.	I-Person
C.	I-Person
Hecker	E-Person
,	O
Der	O
schwarze	O
Tod	O
im	O
vierzehnten	O
Jahrhundert	O
[The	O
in	O
the	O
Fourteenth	O
Century]	O
(Berlin	O
,	O
(Germany):	O
Friedr	O
.	O

Watercourses	O
at	O
several	O
sites	O
inside	O
the	O
Mozambique	S-Location
border	O
were	O
deliberately	O
contaminated	O
with	O
cholera	S-Pathogen
.	O
These	O
biological	O
attacks	O
had	O
little	O
impact	O
on	O
the	O
fighting	O
capability	O
of	O
ZANLA	S-Location
,	O
but	O
caused	O
considerable	O
distress	O
to	O
the	O
local	O
population	O
.	O

Universities	O
and	O
other	O
scientific	O
institutions	O
should	O
develop	O
procedures	O
to	O
monitor	O
scientific	O
activities	O
.	O

A	O
retrospective	O
cohort	O
study	O
in	O
China	S-Location
found	O
that	O
children	O
were	O
as	O
likely	O
to	O
be	O
infected	O
as	O
adults	O
.	O

The	O
system	O
was	O
expected	O
to	O
reduce	O
the	O
burden	O
on	O
general	O
practitioners	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
also	O
incumbent	O
on	O
the	O
community	O
to	O
review	O
their	O
biosafety	O
procedures	O
and	O
to	O
ensure	O
that	O
all	O
laboratories	O
have	O
a	O
culture	O
of	O
biosafety	O
compliance	O
that	O
is	O
critical	O
for	O
protecting	O
laboratory	O
workers	O
and	O
the	O
broader	O
public.	O
"	O

Frieden	S-Person
.	O
H5N1	S-Disease
,	O
is	O
this	O
the	O
same	O
H5N1	S-Disease
that	O
was	O
commonly	O
referred	O
to	O
as	O
bird	B-Disease
flu	E-Disease
or	O
?	O

However	O
,	O
bacteria	O
can	O
also	O
acquire	O
resistance	O
through	O
transformation	O
,	O
as	O
in	O
Streptococcus	B-Pathogen
pneumoniae	E-Pathogen
uptaking	O
of	O
naked	O
fragments	O
of	O
extracellular	O
DNA	O
that	O
contain	O
antibiotic	O
resistance	O
genes	O
to	O
streptomycin	S-Drug
,	O
through	O
transduction	O
,	O
as	O
in	O
the	O
bacteriophage-mediated	O
transfer	O
of	O
tetracycline	O
resistance	O
genes	O
between	O
strains	O
of	O
,	O
or	O
through	O
gene	O
transfer	O
agents	O
,	O
which	O
are	O
particles	O
produced	O
by	O
the	O
host	O
cell	O
that	O
resemble	O
bacteriophage	O
structures	O
and	O
are	O
capable	O
of	O
transferring	O
DNA	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
same	O
year	O
Endicott	S-Person
book	O
was	O
published	O
,	O
Kathryn	B-Person
Weathersby	E-Person
and	O
Milton	B-Person
Leitenberg	E-Person
of	O
the	O
Cold	O
War	O
International	O
History	O
Project	O
at	O
the	O
Woodrow	B-Location
Wilson	I-Location
Center	I-Location
in	I-Location
Washington	E-Location
released	O
a	O
cache	O
of	O
Soviet	O
and	O
Chinese	O
documents	O
that	O
claimed	O
to	O
have	O
revealed	O
that	O
the	O
biowarfare	O
allegation	O
was	O
an	O
elaborate	O
disinformation	O
campaign	O
by	O
the	O
communists	O
.	O

On	O
20	O
July	O
,	O
the	O
last	O
patients	O
were	O
discharged	O
,	O
Reuters	S-Organization
(20	O
July	O
2015).	O
"	O
Liberia	S-Location
:	O
Ebola	S-Disease
Patients	O
Discharged	O
,	O
Last	O
of	O
the	O
Country's	O
Latest	O
Wave"	O
.	O

To	O
create	O
a	O
T1-weighted	O
image	O
,	O
magnetization	O
is	O
allowed	O
to	O
recover	O
before	O
measuring	O
the	O
MR	O
signal	O
by	O
changing	O
the	O
repetition	O
time	O
(TR)	O
.	O

Initially	O
,	O
the	O
letter	O
was	O
dismissed	O
as	O
"	O
some	O
crank	O
trying	O
to	O
get	O
a	O
lot	O
of	O
publicity",Published	O
on	O
December	O
2	O
,	O
1989	O
,	O
Daily	O
News	O
of	O
Los	B-Location
Angeles	E-Location
(CA)	O
GROUP	O
CLAIMS	O
RESPONSIBILITY	O
FOR	O
MEDFLY	O
WOES	O
but	O
there	O
was	O
evidence	O
the	O
group	O
played	O
a	O
role	O
in	O
the	O
infestation	O
.	O

On	O
Wednesday	O
of	O
this	O
week	O
,	O
we	O
learned	O
of	O
another	O
event	O
at	O
CDC	S-Organization
Our	O
influenza	O
laboratory	O
was	O
preparing	O
a	O
less	O
harmful	O
strain	B-Pathogen
of	I-Pathogen
animal	I-Pathogen
influenza	E-Pathogen
for	O
shipment	O
to	O
a	O
partner	O
laboratory	O
.	O

Dr	O
.	O

The	O
committee	O
decided	O
that	O
the	O
conditions	O
for	O
a	O
Public	B-Incident
Health	I-Incident
Emergency	I-Incident
of	I-Incident
International	I-Incident
Concern	E-Incident
()	O
had	O
not	O
at	O
present	O
been	O
met	O
.	O

The	O
advises	O
people	O
to	O
avoid	O
touching	O
the	O
eyes	O
,	O
nose	O
,	O
or	O
mouth	O
with	O
unwashed	O
hands	O
.	O

The	O
lower	O
value	O
of	O
700	O
million	O
is	O
more	O
than	O
the	O
500	O
million	O
people	O
estimated	O
to	O
have	O
been	O
infected	O
by	O
the	O
Spanish	B-Incident
flu	I-Incident
pandemic	E-Incident

Because	O
they	O
are	O
so	O
small	O
,	O
you	O
may	O
not	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
see	O
,	O
smell	O
,	O
or	O
taste	O
them	O
.	O

According	O
to	O
the	O
U.S.	B-Organization
Congress	I-Organization
Office	I-Organization
of	I-Organization
Technology	I-Organization
Assessment	E-Organization
8	O
countries	O
were	O
generally	O
reported	O
as	O
having	O
undeclared	O
offensive	O
biological	O
warfare	O
programs	O
in	O
1995:	O
China	S-Location
,	O
Iran	S-Location
,	O
Iraq	S-Location
,	O
Israel	S-Location
,	O
Libya	S-Location
,	O
North	B-Location
Korea	E-Location
,	O
Syria	S-Location
and	O
Taiwan	S-Location
.	O
Five	O
countries	O
had	O
admitted	O
to	O
having	O
had	O
offensive	O
weapon	O
or	O
development	O
programs	O
in	O
the	O
past:	O
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
,	O
Russia	S-Location
,	O
France	S-Location
,	O
the	O
United	B-Location
Kingdom	E-Location
,	O
and	O
Canada	S-Location
.	O
Offensive	B-Scientific_research_project
BW	I-Scientific_research_project
programs	I-Scientific_research_project
in	I-Scientific_research_project
Iraq	E-Scientific_research_project
were	O
dismantled	O
by	O
Coalition	B-Organization
Forces	E-Organization
and	O
the	O
UN	S-Organization
after	O
the	O
first	O
Gulf	O
War	O
(1990–91)	O
,	O
although	O
an	O
Iraqi	B-Scientific_research_project
military	I-Scientific_research_project
BW	I-Scientific_research_project
program	E-Scientific_research_project
was	O
covertly	O
maintained	O
in	O
defiance	O
of	O
international	O
agreements	O
until	O
it	O
was	O
apparently	O
abandoned	O
during	O
1995	O
and	O
1996	O
.	O

The	O
earliest	O
known	O
person	O
with	O
symptoms	O
was	O
later	O
discovered	O
to	O
have	O
fallen	O
ill	O
on	O
1December	O
2019	O
,	O
and	O
that	O
person	O
did	O
not	O
have	O
visible	O
connections	O
with	O
the	O
later	O
wet	O
market	O
cluster	O
.	O

Tigers	O
and	O
lions	O
at	O
the	O
Bronx	B-Location
Zoo	I-Location
in	I-Location
New	I-Location
York	E-Location
United	B-Location
States	E-Location
,	O
tested	O
positive	O
for	O
the	O
virus	O
and	O
showed	O
symptoms	O
of	O
COVID‑19	S-Disease
,	O
including	O
a	O
dry	B-Phenotype
cough	E-Phenotype
and	O
.	O

A	O
US	B-Organization
Army	E-Organization
report	O
in	O
1981	O
compared	O
two	O
scenarios	O
–	O
16	O
simultaneous	O
attacks	O
on	O
a	O
city	O
by	O
mosquitoes	O
,	O
infected	O
with	O
Yellow	B-Disease
Fever	E-Disease
,	O
and	O
aerosol	O
attack	O
,	O
and	O
assesses	O
their	O
effectiveness	O
in	O
cost	O
and	O
casualties	O
.	O

What	O
has	O
changed	O
in	O
the	O
last	O
two	O
years	O
is	O
our	O
ability	O
to	O
detect	O
it	O
.	O

The	O
outbreak	O
has	O
been	O
blamed	O
for	O
several	O
instances	O
of	O
supply	O
shortages	O
,	O
stemming	O
from	O
globally	O
increased	O
usage	O
of	O
equipment	O
to	O
fight	O
outbreaks	O
,	O
panic	O
buying	O
(which	O
in	O
several	O
places	O
led	O
to	O
shelves	O
being	O
cleared	O
of	O
grocery	O
essentials	O
such	O
as	O
food	O
,	O
toilet	O
paper	O
,	O
and	O
bottled	O
water)	O
,	O
and	O
disruption	O
to	O
factory	O
and	O
logistic	O
operations	O
.	O

The	O
outbreak	O
at	O
the	O
Lanzhou	B-Organization
Veterinary	I-Organization
Research	I-Organization
Institute	E-Organization
was	O
first	O
uncovered	O
in	O
November	O
when	O
some	O
students	O
in	O
the	O
institute's	O
foot	O
and	O
mouth	O
disease	O
research	O
unit	O
noticed	O
that	O
large	O
numbers	O
of	O
their	O
lab	O
mice	O
were	O
infertile	O
,	O
according	O
to	O
The	O
Beijing	B-Organization
News	E-Organization
.	O
The	O
mice	O
tested	O
positive	O
for	O
,	O
as	O
did	O
four	O
students	O
.	O

Many	O
high-consequence	O
pathogens	O
are	O
rarely	O
,	O
or	O
have	O
never	O
been	O
,	O
encountered	O
in	O
real-life	O
situations	O
,	O
meaning	O
that	O
the	O
capacity	O
to	O
carry	O
out	O
the	O
relevant	O
methods	O
is	O
not	O
tested	O
on	O
a	O
regular	O
basis	O
.	O

Health	O
care	O
providers	O
taking	O
care	O
of	O
someone	O
who	O
may	O
be	O
infected	O
are	O
recommended	O
to	O
use	O
standard	O
precautions	O
,	O
contact	O
precautions	O
,	O
and	O
eye	O
protection	O
.	O

More	O
likely	O
and	O
more	O
alarming	O
are	O
weapons	O
for	O
new	O
types	O
of	O
conflicts	O
and	O
warfare	O
scenarios	O
,	O
namely	O
low-intensity	O
warfare	O
or	O
secret	O
operations	O
,	O
for	O
economic	O
warfare	O
or	O
for	O
sabotage	O
activities	O
.	O

Light	O
bulbs	O
containing	O
Bacillus	B-Pathogen
globigii	E-Pathogen
were	O
dropped	O
in	O
's	O
subway	O
system	O
;	O
the	O
result	O
was	O
strong	O
enough	O
to	O
affect	O
people	O
prone	O
to	O
illness	O
(also	O
known	O
as	O
Subway	O
Experiment)	O
.	O

A	O
description	O
is	O
given	O
of	O
a	O
configurable	O
metadata	O
system	O
designed	O
to	O
grow	O
as	O
the	O
project	O
evolves	O
.	O

Critics	O
have	O
said	O
the	O
WHO	S-Organization
handled	O
the	O
pandemic	O
inadequately	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
public	O
health	O
emergency	O
declaration	O
and	O
pandemic	O
classification	O
came	O
too	O
late	O
.	O

A	O
hazardous-materials	O
worker	O
sprays	O
his	O
colleagues	O
on	O
October	O
23	O
,	O
2001	O
,	O
after	O
emerging	O
from	O
an	O
anthrax	S-Disease
search	O
on	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
group	O
,	O
one	O
in	O
every	O
1,800	O
CT	B-Technology
scans	E-Technology
was	O
followed	O
by	O
an	O
excess	O
cancer	O
.	O

And	O
those	O
funds	O
would	O
be	O
deployed	O
rapidly	O
,	O
he	O
said	O
,	O
and	O
accountability	O
would	O
be	O
built	O
in	O
.	O

Risk	O
assessment	O
guidelines	O
include	O
the	O
pathogenicity	O
of	O
the	O
infectious	O
agent	O
,	O
the	O
method	O
of	O
transmission	O
,	O
worker-related	O
risk	O
factors	O
,	O
the	O
source	O
and	O
route	O
of	O
infection	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
design	O
of	O
the	O
laboratory	O
facility	O
.	O

&quot;We	O
have	O
a	O
tendency	O
in	O
this	O
country	O
to	O
react	O
to	O
things	O
after	O
they	O
occur,&quot	O
;	O
said	O
Blue	O
Ribbon	O
panel	O
co	O
-chairman	S-Person
Tom	O
Ridge	O
,	O
former	O
gonnsylvania	O
.	O

Scientists	O
at	O
the	O
center	O
are	O
developing	O
vaccines	O
for	O
swine	B-Pathogen
flu	E-Pathogen
HIV	S-Pathogen
,	O
and	O
Ebola	S-Pathogen
.	O
In	O
February	O
,	O
scientists	O
there	O
wrapped	O
up	O
clinical	O
trials	O
of	O
an	O
Ebola	B-Vaccine
vaccine	E-Vaccine
,	O
according	O
to	O
.	O

Sen	O
.	O

Arnold	S-Person
(2019)	O
estimates	O
at	O
least	O
12	O
million	O
dead.	O
,	O
"	O
Dearth	O
and	O
the	O
Modern	O
Empire:	O
The	O
1918–19	O
Influenza	O
Epidemic	O
in	O
India,	O
"	O
Transactions	O
of	O
the	O
Royal	O
Historical	O
Society	O
29	O
(2019):	O
181–200	O
.	O

They	O
also	O
expect	O
us	O
to	O
adhere	O
to	O
the	O
highest	O
standards	O
possible	O
.	O

Human-to-human	O
transmission	O
was	O
confirmed	O
by	O
the	O
and	O
Chinese	O
authorities	O
by	O
20	O
January	O
2020	O
.	O

Proponents	O
make	O
all	O
sorts	O
of	O
claims	O
about	O
the	O
capacity	O
of	O
biochar	O
to	O
sequester	O
carbon	O
,	O
for	O
which	O
there	O
is	O
little	O
scientific	O
basis	O
,	O
and	O
they	O
fail	O
to	O
consider	O
the	O
impacts	O
of	O
dramatically	O
increasing	O
the	O
demand	O
for	O
plant	O
matter.	O
"	O

Furthermore	O
,	O
expression	O
microarray	O
analysis	O
performed	O
on	O
whole	O
lung	O
tissue	O
of	O
mice	O
infected	O
with	O
the	O
1918	O
HA/NA	O
recombinant	O
showed	O
increased	O
upregulation	O
of	O
genes	O
involved	O
in	O
apoptosis	O
,	O
tissue	O
injury	O
,	O
and	O
oxidative	O
damage	O
.	O

Meanwhile	O
,	O
62	O
countries	O
said	O
they	O
were	O
collecting	O
data	O
on	O
antimicrobial	O
use	O
in	O
animals	O
,	O
and	O
64	O
have	O
limited	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
critically	O
important	O
antimicrobials	O
for	O
growth	O
promotion	O
in	O
animals	O
.	O

Because	O
pigs	O
are	O
more	O
readily	O
infected	O
with	O
avian	O
viruses	O
than	O
are	O
humans	O
,	O
they	O
were	O
suggested	O
as	O
the	O
original	O
recipients	O
of	O
the	O
virus	O
,	O
passing	O
the	O
virus	O
to	O
humans	O
sometime	O
between	O
1913	O
and	O
1918	O
.	O

The	O
Tanzanian	B-Person
Health	I-Person
Minister	I-Person
Ummy	I-Person
Mwalimu	E-Person
stated	O
on	O
3	O
October	O
2019	O
that	O
there	O
was	O
no	O
Ebola	B-Incident
outbreak	E-Incident
in	O
Tanzania	S-Location
.	O
The	O
WHO	S-Organization
were	O
provided	O
with	O
a	O
preparedness	O
update	O
on	O
18	O
October	O
which	O
outlined	O
a	O
range	O
of	O
actions	O
,	O
and	O
included	O
commentary	O
that	O
since	O
the	O
outbreak	O
commenced	O
,	O
there	O
had	O
been	O
"	O
29	O
alerts	O
of	O
Ebola	S-Disease
suspect	O
cases	O
reported	O
,	O
17	O
samples	O
tested	O
and	O
were	O
negative	O
for	O
(including	O
2	O
in	O
September	O
2019)"	O
.	O

Three	O
out	O
of	O
10	O
people	O
with	O
died	O
.	O

In	O
my	O
view	O
,	O
this	O
track	O
record	O
of	O
escapes	O
shows	O
that	O
even	O
the	O
highest	O
biosafety	O
level	O
(	O
BSL-4	S-Platform
is	O
insufficient	O
for	O
working	O
on	O
pathogens	O
that	O
pose	O
a	O
risk	O
of	O
global	O
pandemics	O
on	O
the	O
scale	O
of	O
the	O
Spanish	B-Disease
flu	E-Disease
or	O
worse	O
.	O

CDC	S-Organization
notified	O
potentially	O
exposed	O
personnel	O
as	O
soon	O
as	O
they	O
were	O
identified	O
and	O
referred	O
them	O
to	O
the	O
CDC	B-Organization
health	I-Organization
clinic	E-Organization
or	O
to	O
a	O
local	O
emergency	O
department	O
for	O
evaluation	O
and	O
preventive	O
care	O
.	O

Once	O
the	O
scan	O
data	O
has	O
been	O
acquired	O
,	O
the	O
data	O
must	O
be	O
processed	O
using	O
a	O
form	O
of	O
tomographic	O
reconstruction	O
,	O
which	O
produces	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
cross-sectional	O
images	O
.	O

For	O
instance	O
,	O
"	O
We	O
can	O
do	O
better	O
than	O
the	O
president's	O
way-too-slow	O
response	O
in	O
Puerto	B-Location
Rico	E-Location
and	O
the	O
Virgin	B-Location
Islands	E-Location
after	O
Hurricane	B-Incident
Maria	E-Incident
,	O
"	O
said.	O
"	O
The	O
storm	O
left	O
many	O
people	O
without	O
access	O
to	O
clean	O
water	O
,	O
health	O
care	O
and	O
electricity	O
for	O
months	O
.	O

Rapid	O
spread	O
resulted	O
from	O
an	O
overburdened	O
health	O
care	O
system	O
,	O
a	O
lack	O
of	O
testing	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
large	O
impoverished	O
population	O
,	O
many	O
of	O
whom	O
live	O
in	O
very	O
close	O
proximity	O
and	O
are	O
unable	O
to	O
socially	O
distance	O
or	O
stop	O
work	O
.	O

Lagos	S-Person
,	O
Marisa	S-Person
.	O
"	O
Medfly	O
sightings	O
in	O
Solano	B-Location
County	E-Location
spur	O
quick	O
action	O
to	O
kill	O
pest"	O
,	O
San	O
Francisco	O
Chronicle	O
,	O
September	O
14	O
,	O
2007	O
,	O
accessed	O
February	O
19	O
,	O
2012	O
.	O

CAUTION:	O
&lt;organism	O
name&gt	O
;	O
is	B-Platform
a	I-Platform
Biosafety	I-Platform
L	E-Platform
pathogen	O
.	O

Lenzilumab	S-Drug
an	O
anti-GM-CSF	O
monoclonal	O
antibody	O
,	O
is	O
protective	O
in	O
murine	O
models	O
for	O
CAR	O
T	O
cell-induced	O
CRS	S-Disease
and	O
neurotoxicity	S-Disease
and	O
is	O
a	O
viable	O
therapeutic	O
option	O
due	O
to	O
the	O
observed	O
increase	O
of	O
pathogenic	O
GM-CSF	O
secreting	O
T-cells	O
in	O
hospitalised	O
patients	O
with	O
.	O

Daschle	S-Person
said	O
that	O
his	O
&quot;mounting	O
frustration	O
over	O
the	O
inactiongton	O
on	O
this	O
issue&quot	O
;	O
is	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
reasons	O
he	O
decided	O
to	O
serve	O
on	O
the	O
bipartisan	O
Blue	O
Ribbon	O
Study	O
Panel	O
on	O
Biodefense	O
.	O

UN	B-Organization
News	I-Organization
Centre	E-Organization
.	O
26	O
August	O
2015	O
.	O

There	O
was	O
no	O
major	O
structural	O
damage	O
in	O
the	O
incident	O
and	O
"	O
no	O
work	O
with	O
biological	O
materials	O
was	O
going	O
on	O
there"	O
,	O
the	O
Vektor	S-Organization
statement	O
said	O
.	O

There	O
are	O
about	O
70	O
armed	O
military	O
groups	O
,	O
among	O
them	O
the	O
Alliance	B-Organization
of	I-Organization
Patriots	E-Organization
for	O
a	O
Free	B-Location
and	I-Location
Sovereign	I-Location
Congo	E-Location
and	O
the	O
Mai-Mayi	B-Location
Nduma	E-Location
défense	O
du	O
Congo-Rénové	S-Organization
,	O
in	O
North	B-Location
Kivu	E-Location
.	O
The	O
armed	O
fighting	O
has	O
displaced	O
thousands	O
of	O
individuals	O
.	O

Western	B-Location
Africa	E-Location
On	O
8	O
August	O
2014	O
,	O
a	O
cordon	O
sanitaire	O
,	O
a	O
disease-fighting	O
practice	O
that	O
forcibly	O
isolates	O
affected	O
regions	O
,	O
was	O
established	O
in	O
the	O
triangular	O
area	O
where	O
Guinea	S-Location
,	O
Liberia	S-Location
,	O
and	O
are	O
separated	O
only	O
by	O
porous	O
borders	O
and	O
where	O
70	O
per	O
cent	O
of	O
the	O
known	O
cases	O
had	O
been	O
found	O
.	O

Appointment	O
of	O
Dr	O
.	O
